■
本字幕由網路愛好者聯盟原創翻譯
在保留譯者名單的前提下任何人不需要經得我們的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所產生的後果由您自行承擔
歡迎加入我們 www.ZiMuZu.pub
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h譯
陸修\h\h\h\hCecile12\h\h\h\h麥奇麥奇\h\h\h\hStifflerQ\h\h\h\hRuthchou
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h譯
Amber-Royal\h\h\h\h李逢玉\h\h\h\h裘蒂科默的傑克肖\h\h\h\hhomosapiens\h\h\h\hAmb1992
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(110,216,292,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(110,192,292,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(110,216,292,216))}校對\h&\h後期
刺羅森林\h\h\h\h你以為列
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}■
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}片頭推廣合作洽談：請聯繫普羅米修士郵箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
♪ 日出當頭 ♪
♪ The sun's in the sky ♪
♪ 萬物和氣 ♪
♪ Nothing can go wrong ♪
♪ 揮別冬寂 ♪
♪ Kiss winter goodbye ♪
♪ 夏日悄來 ♪
♪ And sing this summer song ♪
♪ 長養於此 ♪
♪ I was born here, I guess I'll stay ♪
♪ 無處歸去 ♪
♪ Why would I ever go away? ♪
♪ 蜉蝣人生 ♪
♪ Life is a lifelong ♪
♪ 須臾夏日 ♪
♪ Summer's day... ♪
♪ 婉轉流過 ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing all summer long. ♪
-謝謝  -唱得好  唱得好
- Thanks. - Bravo! Bravo!
安可唱首《夏日戀歌》吧
Encore! Uh, "The Summer Song."
他剛剛唱的就是這個
He just played "The Summer Song."
那就再唱一遍吧
Well, play it again, then.
或者隨便唱個"夏"字打頭的歌
Or just any song with "summer" in the title. Doesn't matter.
大家乾杯  我休息一會兒
Uh, cheers, guys. I'm gonna take a bit of a break
稍後回來
and then I'll come back.
昨 日 奇 跡
傑克
Jack.
先生
Sir.
你幹活  幹得怎麼樣了
How are you... enjoying the job?
還不錯  謝謝關心
Yeah, not bad. Good, thanks.
我注意到顧客很喜歡你
I've noticed the customers like you.
是嗎  那很棒  我努力表現得很友善
Okay, great. Yeah, well, I try to be friendly.
我就不一樣
Unlike me.
我發現我就越來越不喜歡你了
I'm increasingly finding I don't like you.
-是嗎  -就是那個鬍子
- Right. - You know, the beard
真讓我心煩
gets on my nerves.
刮一下怎麼了
What's wrong with shaving?
是的  我知道  我想
Yeah, I know. I suppose I... Yeah...
而且我也不喜歡你老是遲到
And I don't like the way you're always late.
我也不喜歡你的衣著
I-I don't like the way you dress.
而且更糟糕的是  我總覺得
And worse, I get the feeling
你覺得在這工作是委屈你了
you think working here is beneath you.
哎  誰讓顧客都喜歡你呢
Oh. But the customers like you.
所以你要是想幹全職的話也可以
So, if you want to go full-time, you can.
好的
Right.
好的  很好
Okay. Well, yeah, great.
我可以考慮考慮
Uh, let me think about that.
或者  還是有一些其他選擇的
Or, eh, here's the alternative, son.
再幹兩周你就可以走了
Two weeks, you're out on your ear.
我可以把活都交給笨拙的卡倫
Yeah. I'll give the job to dozy Karen.
好的
Okay, great.
真不錯
Well, classic. Um...
-我會很快回復您的  -很好
- Yeah, I'll get right back to you. - Good.
有人找你
There's someone to see you.
快點兒  我們還得賣東西
Make it quick. We've got stuff to sell.
你想聽好消息還是壞消息
Do you want the good news or the bad news?
好消息吧
I'm gonna have to say good news,
再來壞的我就受不了了
'cause I don't think I could take any more bad news.
好吧  好消息是
Well, the good news is
緯度音樂節預約你演出啦
you're booked for Latitude Festival.
不是吧
No!
是的  是的
Yes! Yes!
但不是最大的
It's not the biggest...
是薩福克場
It's the, it's the Suffolk Tent.
管他什麼場  這可是緯度節啊
I don't care what tent, it's Latitude!
超棒的音樂節
It's a proper festival!
你真是世界上最棒的經紀人
You are the best manager in the world!
緯度節啊
Latitude!
♪ 我踏上的這條路 ♪
♪ This road that I'm walking, well ♪
♪ 走了許久 ♪
♪ It started young ♪
♪ 一把吉他當行囊 ♪
♪ I found a guitar and then it all begun ♪
♪ 事事順意 ♪
♪ I found all the things I wanted to be ♪
棒極了
Classic.
♪ 趕緊抓住我的手 ♪
♪ So come take my hand ♪
♪ 和我走到路盡頭 ♪
♪ And rock this road with me ♪
♪ 走到頭 ♪
♪ Rock this road ♪
♪ 不放手 ♪
♪ I'm not gonna stop ♪
♪ 走到山腰到頂峰 ♪
♪ Rock this road till I'm at the top ♪
♪ 和我走到路盡頭 ♪
♪ Rock this road, we'll do it right ♪
♪ 夜賞繁星日出頭 ♪
♪ I'm gonna rock this road tonight ♪
♪ 蜿蜒曲折 ♪
♪ Gotta follow this winding road ♪
♪ 一直走 ♪
♪ I gotta follow ♪
♪ 不回頭 ♪
♪ Wherever it goes ♪
♪ 我只得背著行囊 ♪
♪ I guess I'll always carry this load ♪
♪ 天命之選 ♪
♪ That's my fate ♪
♪ 一直走 ♪
♪ I rock this road. ♪
非常感謝緯度節
Uh, accept my gratitude, Latitude.
真是熱鬧
Uh, yeah, it's been a blast.
我覺得《恐龍》唱得真是精彩
I thought "Dinosaur" was particularly strong.
是啊  我大部分都唱對了
Well, yeah, I got most of the words right.
聽我嘶吼
"Hear me roar,
-我是恐龍  -洛基
- I'm a dinosaur." - Rocky!
-你怎麼到這來了  -沒錯  夥計
- What are you doing here? - Yes, mate!
看來那些說你是懶蟲
So everyone who said that you were a lazy,
-廢物  酒鬼  癮君子  -你好
- useless, drug-taking drunk... - Hello.
無所事事  遊手好閒的人都錯了
...who'd never get a job were wrong.
他們的確是錯了
Yes, they were, actually.
我可是幹著有收入的職業
I'm in profitable employment.
一個搖滾機器裡的重要小零件噢
A valued cog in a well-oiled rock machine.
對了  唱得不錯  夥計
Good set, though, mate.
是嗎  你聽了嗎  我沒看見你
Yeah. Did you hear it? I didn't see you.
說實話
I-If I'm totally honest,
我只是在場子後面快速地抽了根煙而已
I only popped by for a quick bong behind the tent.
但是聽到你唱可真是驚喜
But it was a lovely surprise to hear you.
不過我沒全聽
I mean, I didn't hear much of it,
真的  因為
to be honest, 'cause...
在抽著呢  但是真的好
of the bong and stuff, but... yeah.
我看出來了  你還和小艾莉熱乎著呢
Ah, you're still making sweet love to young Ellie, I see.
沒有沒有
No. No.
從來沒有  一次都沒
No, never. Not once.
真是可惜
That's a shame.
她是我經紀人
She's my manager.
你想來我們演唱會的後臺嗎
Hey, do you wanna come backstage for our gig?
-啥  還問啥問啊  -真的嗎
- Wha... Please. - Yeah?
那就走吧
Let's do it, then.
-讓我們上路吧  -好吧
- Let's rock this road. - All right.
你回薩福克多久了
So how long you been back in Suffolk?
其實我一直在努力脫離
Oof. Well, I'm trying to live outside the traditional
傳統的時間觀念
concept of time.
所以大概是幾周  或者幾個月了吧
So, could be weeks, could me months,
也有可能是一年半載的了  沒印象了
could be a year and a half, no idea.
到了
Oh, here we are.
謝謝大家
Thank you so much.
所以你具體是幹什麼的
So what exactly do you do?
確保一切工作井然有序
Make sure everything runs like clockwork.
-維護設備  -好吧
- Service the equipment. - Right.
做做三明治  泡泡茶
Make sandwiches, make teas.
天啊
Uh... Oh, Christ.
不好意思
Sorry.
不好意思  不好意思  邁克爾
Sorry. Sorry, Michael.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
好滴叭
Fair do's.
被炒了
Got fired.
替我跟艾莉打個招呼吧
Give Ellie one for me, yeah?
-不  我們真的不  -回見
- No, really, we don't... - Catch you later.
完美的一天
Oh, great day.
Yeah, great day.
不過  艾爾  我們該停下了
Though, Elle, we should stop now.
我受不了了
I can't do this anymore.
別說傻話了
Don't be stupid.
你只是需要一個更大的場子
You're gonna need a bigger tent.
可以了  夠了  你不能再這樣裝作
No, okay, stop. You gotta stop pretending
活在一個大故事裡  結尾總是大團圓
that we're in a thrilling story with a big, exciting end.
我們只是小人物  該結束了
We're in a little story and it ends now.
我想我在我的歌裡聽到了一些特別的東西
I think I hear something special in my songs,
你也覺得你聽到了特別的東西
you think you hear something special,
這也是我愛你的地方
and I love you for it.
但沒有其他人聽到  從沒有人聽到
But no one else does. No one ever has.
尼克喜歡聽《夏日戀歌》啊
Uh, Nick loves "The Summer Song."
尼克是個出了名的大蠢蛋
Nick is famously a world-class moron.
直到現在都沒有人  那以後也不會有了
If it hasn't happened by now, it's not going to.
除非奇跡發生
It'll take a miracle.
奇跡會發生的
Miracles happen.
我認真的
I mean it.
我是很認真地在談這個
This is a serious moment for me.
絕對不可能
This is just absolutely not happening.
聽著  我不可能成為我們小時候幻想的明星
Look, I can't be the star that we thought I could be at 14,
我們十四歲  在學校大禮堂
on that day in the school hall
我翻唱了很好聽的《迷牆》
when I sang a pretty cool cover of "Wonderwall"
而你就在後臺
and you were there, backstage.
-風太大了聽不清  -好吧  但真的
- I'm not hearing a word. - Okay, but look.
這個  就是我最後一場了
This, this was my last gig.
而且我很高興你一直陪著我
And I'm so happy you were there.
這就是我們的漫長蜿蜒路的終點了
This is the end of our long and winding road.
世界上充滿了奇跡的  真的
Come on! The world is full of miracles.
比如呢
Like what?
本尼迪克·康伯巴奇成了個性感的明星
Benedict Cumberbatch becoming a sex symbol.
你會改變主意的
You'll change your mind.
我不會的  是時候開始更好的生活了
I won't. This is the start of a better life.
而且我現在感覺很自在
And I'm... feeling perky about it.
晚安  搖滾明星
Night-night, rock star.
你也晚安
Yeah. Night-night.
你還好吧  夥計
You all right, mate?
只允許幾分鐘  好嗎
Just a few minutes, okay?
我可以只說一件事嗎
Can I just say one thing?
只是想  警告你
Just to... warn you.
我和醫生聊過了  他說你
I've spoken with the doctor and you,
你還能下地的
you will walk again.
但你的鬍子
But you have lost your beard
和兩顆大門牙  沒了
and, um, two big teeth.
而且儘管這是件令人悲傷的事情
And even though it should be sad,
但還是很好笑
it's actually very funny, unfortunately.
所以除了所有的痛苦和不便
So despite all the pain and inconvenience,
也沒有人會可憐你的
you're not even gonna get any sympathy.
人們只會嘲笑你
People will just laugh at you.
怎麼了
What happened?
不知道
No one knows.
全球都這樣
It was all over the world.
斷電斷了12秒
Electricity flicked off for 12 seconds.
就在那一瞬間  有一個巴士撞了你
You were just unlucky that at that exact moment,
真是不幸
a big bus hit you.
你記不記得他們覺得
You know, the weird thing they thought
2000年的午夜會有怪事發生
was gonna happen at midnight when we hit 2000?
-是啊  西元2000年  -還真發生了
- Oh, yeah, Y2K. - It sort of happened.
是很重大的新聞  但是你完全錯過了
It was very big news which, um, you missed entirely.
因為車禍
Because of the bus.
好了  我得回學校了
Right. I've gotta get back to school.
-艾爾  -怎麼了
- Elle? - Yeah?
謝謝你這麼照顧我
Thanks for taking such good care of me.
客氣了  我過會兒回來
You're welcome. I'll come back later.
等我64歲的時候
Will you still need me,
你還會需要我  照顧我嗎
will you still feed me, when I'm 64?
這可說不準  我得考慮考慮
I don't know. I'll think about it.
-為什麼是64歲  -你這樣說是什麼意思
- Why 64? - What do you mean?
就是  算了  當我沒說
It's just... oh, forget it.
你是什麼意思  為什麼是64歲
What do you mean, "Why 64?"
我覺得車禍就是上帝給我的資訊
I think the accident was a message from God.
是的  他非常生氣
Yeah, he was very angry.
艾爾  你覺得我被巴士撞上
Elle, you think me getting hit by a bus
是上帝在告訴我不要回去教書了嗎
was God's way of telling me not to go back to teaching?
正是
Exactly.
簡直難以置信  太神奇了
Incredible. It's amazing.
你知道嗎  上帝喜歡你的一些天賦
You know, God loves your stuff.
聽著  如果上帝真的對我有絲毫的興趣
Look, if God had been remotely interested in my stuff,
他就會曾經  是的  哪怕只有一次
he would've once, right, just once,
讓除了我媽媽之外的人給我寫一封粉私信
had someone write me a fan letter who wasn't my mum.
或除了我之外的其他人
Or me.
是的
Yeah.
我沒有說要成為甲殼蟲樂隊
I didn't ask to be The Beatles,
你知道嗎  我只想要哪怕一次起立鼓掌
you know, I just wanted once to have a standing ovation
而不是那些本來就站在酒吧邊的人的掌聲
not given by people who were already standing at the bar.
成為什麼
Be the what?
-噢  天呐  -噢  對喔
- Oh, my God. - Oh, yeah.
卡羅爾  快過來看
Carol, come and look!
我知道艾莉說過很搞笑
I know Ellie said it was funny,
但沒有人提過看起來竟然如此搞笑
but no one mentioned visual humor of this quality.
傑克  噢  天呐  你的牙齒
Jack! Oh, my God! Your teeth.
茄子  噢  哇哦
Cheese! Oh, wow.
快拿禮物  禮物
Presents, presents,
-禮物  -禮物  禮物  是的
- presents. - Mm, presents, presents. Yes, yes.
是真的  我們給你帶了些禮物
It's true, we have bought you presents.
真令人興奮  顯而易見  他們
Exciting. Well, they have, obviously.
工作很忙  是的
Huge work week. Yeah, yeah.
來看看我們有什麼
What do we have here?
好的  好的
Okay, okay, okay.
因為你失去了門牙  所以  你明白的
Because you lost your teeth. That's... Yeah, I know.
所以才那麼搞笑  好吧
That's why that's funny. Okay.
-第二件  -你從哪兒買到的
- Number two. - Where did you get that?
因為你被巴士撞了  我記得
'Cause you got hit by a bus. Yeah, I remember.
你記得嗎
Do you?
-好笑死個人了  -記得
- Hilarious. - Yeah.
好了  還有一個
All right. One more.
我在上面簽了你的名字  別擔心
I've signed your name, don't worry.
是的  還有一個
One more, yes.
我不知道這會是什麼
I don't know what this one could possibly be.
我也不知道
Oh, my... Neither do I. No idea.
我的意思是  我覺得可能是某種雪鏟
I mean, I'm thinking some sort of snow shovel.
或者沒有腿的小長頸鹿
Or a... tiny little giraffe with no legs.
打開它  打開它
Just open it, open it, open it.
好的
Okay.
因為你被巴士撞了
'Cause yours got run over by a bus.
隨便彈點什麼
Well, play something.
是的  彈點什麼  來吧
Yes, play something. Come on.
就彈《夏日戀歌》  讓我們忘記這些經歷
Play "The Summer Song." Let me get rid of this.
是什麼在滴答滴答搖擺
What's tickin' and tockin' and rockin'?
-是的  -他在這裡做什麼
- Yeah! - Oh! What is he doing here?
他被解雇了  現在和我們在一起
Yeah, he got sacked. He's staying with us,
睡沙發  真是個災難
sleeping on the sofa. That is a disaster
也許他會一直住下去
that could last forever...
是的  錯誤的決定
Yep. Terrible decision.
是的  它會毀了你一生
That's right. ...and ruin your entire life.
絕對是
Absolutely.
真高興你還活著
Hey, really glad you're not dead, man.
他有了一副新吉他
He's got a new guitar.
他準備唱歌
He's gonna play a song.
一個好的吉他需要配上一首好歌
A great guitar requires a great song.
♪ 昨日 ♪
♪ Yesterday ♪
♪ 一切煩惱仿佛那麼遙遠 ♪
♪ All my troubles seemed so far away ♪
♪ 如今卻好像都纏繞著我不肯離去 ♪
♪ Now it seems as though they're here to stay ♪
♪ 我沉迷於昨日 ♪
♪ Oh, I believe in yesterday ♪
繼續唱
Go on.
♪ 突然間 ♪
♪ Suddenly ♪
♪ 我已不再是曾今的自己 ♪
♪ I'm not half the man I used to be ♪
♪ 陰雲籠罩著我的一切 ♪
♪ There's a shadow hanging over me ♪
♪ 昨日來的那麼突然 ♪
♪ Oh, yesterday came suddenly ♪
♪ 她為何離去 ♪
♪ Why she had to go ♪
♪ 我無從知曉 ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ 她也不曾提起 ♪
♪ She wouldn't say ♪
♪ 或許是我說錯過什麼 ♪
♪ I said something wrong ♪
♪ 現在的我是多麼渴望往昔 ♪
♪ Now I long for yesterday. ♪
天呐
Oh, my...
這究竟是什麼歌
Wha... What the hell was that?
《昨日》
"Yesterday."
這是我聽過最好聽的歌之一
That was one of the most beautiful songs I've ever heard.
我的意思是雖然還有點淩亂  但很好聽
Yeah. I mean, it's a bit-bit sloppy, but it's sweet.
你什麼時候寫的這歌
Oh. When did you write that?
這不是我寫的
I didn't write it.
是保羅·麥卡特尼寫的
Paul McCartney wrote it,
甲殼蟲
The Beatles.
誰
Who?
甲殼蟲
The Beatles.
什麼
The what?
約翰  保羅  喬治和林戈  甲殼蟲
John, Paul, George and Ringo, The Beatles.
哪個甲殼蟲
Which beetles is this?
昆蟲甲殼蟲還是汽車甲殼蟲
The insect beetles or the car Beetles?
流行樂隊甲殼蟲  尼克  幫幫我
The pop group Beatles... Nick, help me out here.
是的  對的
Right. Yes.
音樂家都有這麼個臭毛病
Um, there's this problem with musicians.
他們覺得每個人都對流行樂隊瞭若指掌
They presume everyone else has this encyclopedic knowledge of obscure pop,
這讓你覺得自己很愚蠢
make you feel stupid
尤其是你沒聽過這樂隊名字的時候
when you haven't heard of bands, you know,
比如中性牛奶飯店樂隊  單聲道樂隊
like Neutral Milk Hotel, or, uh, The Monophonics,
或者  甲殼蟲樂隊
or, in this case, The Beatles.
這是我聽過的最複雜的玩笑了
Wow, this is the most complicated joke I've ever heard.
但  確實是好歌
Nice song, though.
-不能說是好歌  -不  是好歌
- It's not a nice song. - No, it is, mate.
不要因為你長得像卡通人物就貶低自己
Don't do yourself down just 'cause you look like a cartoon character.
這真的是非常好的一首歌
It's-it's a very nice song.
這不是一首非常好的歌  尼克
It's not a very nice song, Nick.
這是有史以來寫出來的最棒的歌之一
It's one of the greatest songs ever written.
這又不是酷玩樂隊的歌  不是《牢記你》
Well, it's not Coldplay. It's not "Fix You."
這當然不是《牢記你》  卡羅爾
It's not bloody "Fix You," Carol,
這是一件偉大的藝術作品
it's a great, great work of art.
有人突然變得傲慢自大了
Wow, somebody suddenly got very cocky.
那首歌真的很優美
That song was exquisite.
我之前怎麼會從來沒有聽過呢
How come I've never heard it before?
好吧  我不知道你們在玩什麼遊戲
Okay, I don't know what you guys are playing at,
但是這真的太奇怪了  而且太不公平了
but this is so weird, a-and quite unfair,
而且我失去了兩顆門牙
in light of me having lost two teeth,
看起來像沒有牙的兔子
looking like a sort of reverse rabbit.
而且我有很多藥要吃
I-I'm on pretty heavy medication.
讓我下車
Just let me out.
好吧
All right.
我以為你願意吃藥
I thought you liked the medication.
是的  我是願意吃藥
Yeah, I do love the medication.
我真的不知道你在生什麼氣
I really don't know what you're cross about.
傑克
Jack...
天呐
Oh, Christ.
不可能  不可能
No way. No way.
好吧
Okay. All right.
什麼
What?
好吧
Okay.
一定是在耍我
Oh... you are having me on.
鮑威  拜克  海灘男孩
"Bowie," "Beck," "Beach Boys."
不  這不可能
No. Stop it.
混蛋
Oh, fuck off!
不
No!
讓我們試試
Let's try...
好的
Good.
滾石樂隊還在
Still rolling.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
上帝保佑你  唐納德
God bless you, Donald.
好的
Okay.
不
No.
好吧  讓我們再看看
Okay, let's just...
怪不得
Well, that figures.
艾爾
Elle!
傑克
Jack.
-怎麼了  -你真不知道甲殼蟲樂隊嗎
-What...? -Do you genuinely not know who The Beatles are?
真的不知道
Genuinely.
好吧
Okay.
那我現在處在一個非常複雜的境地
Then I'm in a really, really, really complicated situation.
一會兒見
See you soon.
睡衣不錯
Nice pajamas.
傑克
Jack!
神呐  不知道
Christ. I don't even know
我現在還能不能記清歌詞
if I can remember the words to the songs.
好吧  埃莉諾·瑞格
Okay. "Eleanor Rigby...
埃莉諾·瑞格：甲殼蟲樂隊的一首歌
埃莉諾·瑞格住在教堂
"Eleanor Rigby lives in a church,
在一個舉辦婚禮的房間
in a room where the wedding..."
不  不對
No.
埃莉諾·瑞格  縫著她的襪子
"Eleanor Rigby, darning her socks in the...
在一間房裡
In a room where..."
不  她有嗎
No, does... does she have...?
她有襪子嗎
Does she have socks?
我真的要這樣做嗎
Am I gonna do this?
我可以這樣做嗎
Can I do this?
-你說  -四和一
- Yeah? - Four and one.
四和一  漂亮  這是我想聽的答案
Four and one. Beautiful. That's music to my ears.
那接下來  我們的公約數是多少
Right, now what is our common, uh, factor...
老師  窗戶外面有人
Miss, there's someone at the window.
-什麼  -窗戶  窗戶
- Sorry? - The window, the window.
對哦
Um... Yes. Right.
大家稍等一分鐘
Can you all just give me just one second?
我想聽你們說出18的約數
I want... If there's any more factors of, um, 18, I wanna hear 'em.
-怎麼了  -我還想再做一次演出
-Yes? -I may do one more gig.
我覺得我可能有一些新歌了
I think I may have got some, like, new songs.
老師  這是你男朋友嗎
Is that your boyfriend, miss?
不  不是
No!
夠了  他不是我男朋友  別喊了
Enough! He is not my boyfriend! That is enough.
♪ 重返校園  麥克斯維爾又在戲弄人 ♪
♪ Back in school again, Maxwell plays the fool again ♪
♪ 老師很生氣 ♪
♪ Teacher gets annoyed ♪
太棒了  又一首
Yes! Another one.
老師  你男朋友丟下你跑了
Your boyfriend's left you, miss.
尷尬了
Awkward!
你說得對  確實很尷尬
You're right, that was very awkward.
不過  我們繼續上課吧
But let's keep going!
♪ 他是個貨真價實的流浪漢 ♪
♪ He's a real nowhere man ♪
♪ 端坐在屬於他的無人之境 ♪
♪ Sitting in his nowhere land ♪
但是  他究竟坐在那幹嘛
What did he do there, though?
♪ 我醒來  狼狽地從床上爬起來 ♪
♪ Woke up, fell out of bed ♪
♪ 抓了把  梳了梳頭
♪ Dragged a... neh... across my head ♪
-有人嗎  -有
-Yoo-hoo! -Yeah?
顯然這些便利條不能當牆紙用
Oh. Sure those Post-it Notes aren't gonna mark the wallpaper?
這不是我現在最重要的事情
Eh, that's not exactly my top priority at the moment.
現在你最重要的事情是
Oh, well, your top priority should be
給你自己補幾顆新牙
getting yourself some new teeth. Aw.
我給你帶了瓶百事
I brought you a Pepsi.
-沒買到可樂嗎  -什麼
- Have we not got any Coke? - What?
可口可樂
Coca-Cola.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're saying.
如果你餓了就下樓
Come downstairs if you're hungry.
明白了
Gotcha.
你覺得你能
Do you reckon you could, like, make 'em look,
讓它們變得更好看嗎
you know, better than before?
我只是為了重振我的音樂事業
It's just, I'm hoping to relaunch my music thing...
傑克  我是個牙醫  不會變戲法
I'm a dentist, Jack, not a magician.
讓我們試下紅牙具
Let's try the red.
你父親是我的首例病人
Your dad was my first-ever patient.
我可指著他們那種人吃飯
I only survived because of people like him.
很好
That's right.
我很少
I only coped...
合攏嘴巴
Clamp.
尋求朋友幫助
...with a little help from my friends.
那
So, um...
我想我們同意了
uh, I thought we'd agreed.
嗯  我們達成一致了  老爸
Yeah, well, we had, Dad.
但是我寫了很多新歌  我想
But I've-I've got a bunch of new songs, and I thought people
大家會喜歡聽
might like to hear 'em.
很好  為什麼
Huh. Well, why, uh,
你為什麼不唱一首給我們聽
why don't you play one for us?
好
Okay.
-你確定要聽  -嗯  必須要聽
- You sure? - Yeah, of course.
我和你老爸很喜歡聽你的歌
Me and your dad love hearing your... things.
對吧  親愛的
Don't we, darling?
當然
We do.
好  好
Okay. Okay,
好
Okay.
好  這首歌叫《順其自然》
Right, this is called... "Let It Be."
♪ 當我身處逆境時 ♪
♪ When I find myself in times of trouble ♪
♪ 母親瑪麗來到我身邊 ♪
♪ Mother Mary comes to me ♪
♪ 說著 ♪
♪ Speaking... ♪
抱歉  親愛的
Oh. Oh, sorry, love.
我去開門
I'll get it. Mmm.
儘管被打斷了  還是個很棒的開頭
Good start, though.
非常棒
Very pretty.
-茜拉  -泰瑞
- Hello, Sheila. - Terry!
-進來  親愛的  -很高興見到你
- Come in, love. - Nice to see you.
泰瑞來了
Oh. It's Terry!
-泰瑞  -你好  -你好
- Terry. - Hello. - Hiya.
傑克正在為我們演奏一首新歌
Jack's just playing us a new song.
真的嗎  我還以為  還以為他放棄了
Oh, really? I thought, I thought he'd given up.
對  不  他寫了些新歌
Yeah, no, well, he's got some new songs.
他  嗯
He... Yeah.
-這首歌叫啥來著  -《放任不管》
- Uh, what's this one called? Uh, - "Leave It Be."
-《順其自然》  -很棒
- "Let It Be." - Oh, excellent.
那就搖滾起來吧  傑克
Well, rock on, Jack.
這首歌沒什麼搖滾風  但
Well, it's not very rocky, but...
♪ 當我身處逆境時 ♪
♪ When I find myself in times of trouble... ♪
你要喝點啥嗎  泰瑞
Would you like a drink, Terry?
老爸
Dad...
我聽著呢
Well, I'd already heard that bit.
抱歉  傑克
Sorry, Jack.
你父親不太禮貌
Your dad's a rude man.
請給我拿杯啤酒  傑德
Yeah, I'll get a beer, please, Jed.
很棒
Excellent.
好
Right.
你繼續  傑克o
Carry on, Jacko.
我一會兒就回來
I'll be back.
麻煩把啤酒裝在玻璃杯子裡
Can I get it in a glass?
就是裝杯子裡
Glass it is!
-好  -大家都準備好聽我演奏了嗎
- Right, - is everyone else settled?
-嗯  -嗯  嗯  嗯
- Yeah, - yeah, yeah. Yes!
快點  親愛的  聽眾等得快不耐煩了
Hurry it up, darling, you're losing the crowd.
好
Okay.
♪ 當我身處逆境時 ♪
♪ When I find myself in times of trouble ♪
♪ 母親瑪麗來到我身邊 ♪
♪ Mother Mary comes to me... ♪
抱歉
Ooh, sorry.
抱歉  傑克  都賴我
Sorry, Jack. That's me.
抱歉  我的錯
Sorry, my fault.
瑪姬打來的
Oh, it's Marge. Oh.
喂  親愛的
Hello, love.
我在傑德夫婦家
I'm just at, uh, Jed and Sheila's house
聽著傑克的新歌聽他的便吧
listening to Jack's new song. "Let Him Be."
-是《順其自然》  -《順其自然》
- "Let It Be." - "Let It Be."
不  很顯然  他打算再演奏一遍
No, well, apparently, he's-he's started up again.
對
Yeah.
對  我知道
Uh, yeah, I know.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
對  我知道
Yeah, I know.
-我知道  -你知道什麼
- I know. - What do you know?
聽著  等他演奏結束時
Listen, I'll-I'll... I'll call you back
我再給你回個電話  好嗎
when it's over, all right?
那就這樣吧
Oh, all right, then.
好  一會兒再聯繫
Yeah. Okay. See you in a minute.
-開始你的表演  年輕人  -你能
- Carry on broadcasting, young man. - Maybe start
跳過開頭進行演奏嗎  我都聽三遍了
after the first bit. I've heard it three times now.
如果合適的話  我會從高潮部分唱起的
If it's okay, I'm gonna go from the top.
你自便  兒子
Please yourself, son.
那麼我們能聽你唱夏之歌嗎
Then, maybe we can have "Summer Song."
我天  這首歌是《順其自然》呀
Christ! This is "Let It Be."
你們是世界上第一批聽這首歌的人
You're the first people on Earth to hear this song.
這就像你們親眼看著達芬奇在
This is like watching da Vinci paint The Mona Lisa
創作那幅舉世傑作蒙娜麗莎一樣
right in front of your bloody eyes.
你們就不能安靜一會嗎
Can you not just be quiet for a single second?
瑪姬來了
Ooh, that'll be Marge.
是瑪喬麗來了啊
Oh, Marjorie! Well,
她說了要過來拜訪
she said she was gonna come round,
那我來  對  我去燒水
so I'll... Oh, yeah. Oh, I'll put the kettle on.
-你好  -你好  你好  親愛的
- Hi! - Hello. Hello, love.
-你好  -你好  -最近過得怎樣
- Hi. - Hi. - How are you?
-快進來  快進來  -還不錯
- Come in, come in. - Well, that went well.
-這咖啡不錯  -謝謝
- Oh, that's good coffee. - Thank you.
-很好  -先把水燒上
- Good. - Put the kettle on,
這是我剛寫的一首新歌
This is a new song I've just written.
♪ 是的  我要告訴你一些事 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, I'll tell you somethin' ♪
♪ 我認為你能明白 ♪
♪ I think you'll understand ♪
♪ 當我說那些事時 ♪
♪ When I say that somethin' ♪
♪ 我想抓住你的手 ♪
♪ I want to hold your hand ♪
♪ 低語著智慧的之詞 ♪
♪ Whisper words of wisdom ♪
♪ 順其自然吧 ♪
♪ Let it be ♪
天呐
Oh, God.
對  將堆起來的裝袋然後放到拖車上
Right, bag stack them up and put them on the trailer.
打擾了
Excuse me.
-什麼事  -你是他的經紀人嗎
- Yeah? - Um, are you the manager?
是啊
Uh-huh.
我叫加文
I'm Gavin.
你還好嗎
You okay?
我才是問題所在
It's me, that's the problem.
那就是可怕的真相  真相就是
That's the awful truth. The revelation
我覺得這些歌曲很棒  卻沒人感興趣
I know the songs are strong, but no one's interested still.
傑克·馬利卡的問題
Jack Malik's the problem.
-你說的不對  -就是這樣
- That's not true. - It is.
我只是沒有那種東西  這就是
I just don't have the "it" that's the difference
Jay-Z：美國著名說唱歌手
Jay-Z和Jay-其他的區別
between Jay-Z and... Jay-Y.
那你怎麼解釋這個
Well, then, how do you explain this?
你將會成為一名唱片藝人  ·馬利卡先生
You're gonna be a recording artist, Mr. Malik.
♪ 因為她傾心於你 ♪
♪ Because she loves you ♪
♪ 你知道那將十分美妙 ♪
♪ And you know that can't be bad ♪
♪ 對  她傾心於你 ♪
♪ Yes, she loves you ♪
我願意免費幫助你
I'd be very happy to help for free.
我的錄音室  供你使用
My studio, at your service.
加文  你真棒
Gavin. You're cool.
真的嗎
am i?
♪ 她傾心於你  對  對  對 ♪
♪ She loves you, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 擁有那樣的愛 ♪
♪ And with a love like that ♪
♪ 你覺得應該感到慶倖 ♪
♪ You know you should be glad ♪
♪ 擁有那樣的愛 ♪
♪ With a love like that ♪
♪ 你覺得應該 ♪
♪ You know you should... ♪
♪ 感到慶倖 ♪
♪ Be glad... ♪
♪ 對  對  對 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 對  對  對  對 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. ♪
不錯  不錯  不錯  成功了
Yes, yes, yes, we got it!
不錯  我們做到了
Yes, we have reached the mountaintop!
♪ 對  對  對  對 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah! ♪
你喜歡嗎  加文
Do you like it, Gavin?
我太喜歡了  艾莉
I absolutely love it, Ellie.
傑克  你還寫了其它的歌嗎
Jack, you got any more songs?
還有一兩首吧
One or two.
♪ 是的  我要告訴你一些事 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, I'll tell you somethin' ♪
♪ 我認為你能明白 ♪
♪ I think you'll understand ♪
♪ 當我說那些事時 ♪
♪ When I say that somethin' ♪
♪ 我想抓住你的手 ♪
♪ I want to hold your hand ♪
♪ 現在  讓我抓住你的手 ♪
♪ Now, let me hold your hand ♪
♪ 我想抓住你的手 ♪
♪ I want to hold your hand ♪
♪ 當我觸碰你的時候 ♪
♪ And when I touch you ♪
♪ 我從心底感覺到開心 ♪
♪ I feel happy inside ♪
♪ 這就是那種所謂愛的感覺 ♪
♪ It's such a feelin' that my love ♪
♪ 我情不自禁 ♪
♪ I can't hide ♪
♪ I can't hide... ♪
♪ 她才17歲 ♪
♪ Well, she was just 17 ♪
♪ 你懂我的意思 ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ 她的容顏 ♪
♪ And the way she looked ♪
♪ 簡直無與倫比 ♪
♪ Was way beyond compare ♪
♪ 他不會與其他人共舞 ♪
♪ She wouldn't dance with another ♪
♪ 哦 ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ 當我看到她站在那兒 ♪
♪ When I saw her standing there. ♪
請聽一下  謝謝
Have a listen. Thank you.
-真讓人興奮  -多少錢
- Hey. Exciting. - How much?
免費
Oh, no charge.
買東西就送
Uh, it's free with any purchase.
買士力架送  買合裝包商品也送
Songs with your Snickers, music with your multipacks.
-謝謝  -買幾塊切達乳酪也送
- Oh, thank you. - Tunes with your chunks of cheddar cheese.
-傑克  -這是個有趣的小故事
- Jack! - And here's a lovely little story.
傑克  你在洛斯托夫特的
Jack, you work in the wholesale warehouse
批發商城工作
in Lowestoft.
我們聽說零售店的會員除了得到
And we hear members of the retail trade have been getting
幾盒雀巢咖啡和洗衣粉之外
a free CD along with their jumbo boxes
-還免費得到了一張CD  -對
- of Nescafé and washing powder. - That's right.
但你現在要為我們唱首新歌
But you're gonna sing us a new song now.
那有請我們的批發銷售歌者  傑克·馬利卡
So, here's Jack Malik, the singing wholesaler,
演唱歌曲《在我生命裡》
"In My Life."
♪ 但所有這些愛人和朋友 ♪
♪ But of all these friends and lovers ♪
♪ 他們誰都不能 ♪
♪ There is no one ♪
♪ 和你相比 ♪
♪ Compares with you ♪
♪ 這些記憶也就失去了它們的意義 ♪
♪ And these memories lose their meaning ♪
♪ 當我對愛情感到陌生 ♪
♪ When I think of love as something new ♪
♪ 雖然我知道我從未失去 ♪
♪ Though I know I'll never lose affection ♪
♪ 那些故人和往事 ♪
♪ For people and things that went before ♪
♪ 我知道我會經常駐足回想 ♪
♪ I know I'll often stop and think about them ♪
♪ 在我的生命中 ♪
♪ In my life ♪
♪ 我愛你更多 ♪
♪ I love you more. ♪
太棒了
Beautiful.
沒提大號的小仙女洗衣液
No mention of, uh, jumbo-sized Fairy liquid,
也還是首好歌
but nice work.
你有想過寫批發方面的歌嗎
You ever thought about doing a wholesale-based song?
沒有  沒有
Not really, no.
你可以命名為《在我的批發商城裡》
You could call it, uh, "In My Warehouse"
來代替《在我的生命裡》
instead of "In My Life."
現在  是時間讓我們看看
Now, time to find out what's happening
在凱瑞的廚房發生了什麼
in Kerry's Kitchen.
大家好  這裡是凱瑞
G'day, everyone. It's Kerry here.
滾石樂隊或大衛·鮑威的每一首歌
I could've written every song of the Rolling Stones
我都能寫出來
or David Bowie.
但我永遠都只能是洛斯多夫特的倉庫管理員
I'll always just be Lowestoft's warbling warehouseman.
不  別這麼想
Oh, no, don't.
-那不是真的  -顯然是的
- That's not true. - So obviously is.
那首歌真的很美
That song was really beautiful.
你寫的是誰
Who-who did you write it about?
在這兒停車  停車
Stop here. Stop the car.
艾爾
Elle.
關於這些歌
These songs. Mm.
有些事你應該知道
There's something about 'em you should know.
你好
Oh. Hi.
你好  我是那個音樂家艾德·希蘭
Hi... it's the musician... Ed Sheeran.
-請您再說一遍  -艾德·希蘭
- I beg your pardon. - Ed Sheeran.
那個音樂家
I'm a musician.
我知道  不  說真的  你是誰
Yeah, no, seriously though, who is it?
可能是信號不好  我一會兒打回給你
This must be a bad line, I'll-I'll call you back.
是誰啊
Who was it?
他說他是那個音樂家艾德·希蘭
He said it was Ed Sheeran, the musician.
那應該是尼克了
That'll be Nick.
尼克
Nick!
不  又是艾德·希蘭
No, it's Ed Sheeran again.
是啊  我能和卡羅爾說話嗎
Yeah, can I speak to Carol, please?
這裡沒有叫卡羅爾的人
There's no one called Carol here.
除非那裡有  她永遠在那兒
Except there is. She's always there.
好吧  夥計  我不跟你爭了
Okay, mate, um, I'll leave it there.
你今晚在電視上的表演很精彩
Amazing performance tonight though, on TV.
那首歌《在我的生命中》真的很美
That song, "In My Life," that was really beautiful.
他說什麼了
What did he say?
他說他很喜歡《在我的生命中》
He said he really enjoyed "In My Life."
卡羅爾說了什麼
And what did Carol say?
-她不在那裡  -她永遠在那裡
- She wasn't there. - She's always there.
我想可能真的是艾德·希蘭
I think it might've been Ed Sheeran.
那個音樂家嗎
The musician?
你好
Hi.
你好  我是艾德
Hello. I'm Ed.
-傑克在嗎  -好的
- Um, is Jack here? - Oh. Right.
我去看看他睡了沒有  稍等  親愛的
I'll see if he's up. Just wait there, love.
傑克
Jack!
-有人找你  -是誰
- It's for you. - Who is it?
他叫艾德
His name's Ed.
他有一張友善的臉
He's got a nice, friendly face.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
進來吧
C... Uh, come in.
你的襯衫穿反了
Your shirt's inside out.
老天
Oh, Christ.
我們應該
Uh, we should...
所以  聽著  很抱歉就這樣闖進來
So, uh, look, I'm sorry to barge in like this.
不  沒關係  你知道的
No, no, uh, major pop stars
流行歌星經常登門拜訪的
are always dropping round, you know?
Lady Gaga都不肯走
Lady Gaga won't leave us alone.
你很有趣
You're funny.
至少看起來很有趣
Well, funny-looking, at least.
是的  所以  不管怎樣  我住
Yeah, so, anyway, I live, uh,
我住在本地  我在電視上看到了你的歌
I live locally, and I saw your song on TV.
真的很不錯
And it was really good.
所以我穀歌了你
So I googled you,
我在倉庫網站上聽了你的歌
and I listened to your songs on the warehouse website.
那些甚至更好
And they were even better.
天哪  謝謝
Gosh, thanks.
當我不存在
All right, don't mind me.
所以  我將支援演出歌手從
So, I've had the support act drop out
歐洲巡演中移除了
of the European leg of the tour,
我想你是否能考慮一下
and I was wondering if you'd consider it.
考慮一下什麼
Consider what?
開場演出
Being the opening act.
-你的演唱會  真的嗎  -沒有
- For you, seriously? - Nope.
是啊  何嘗不可呢
Yeah, why not?
什麼時候開始
W-Wha... When would I start?
星期二
Tuesday.
你知道酸黃瓜在哪裡嗎
Do you know where the pickle is?
不
No.
二  什麼  星期二
No. Tu... What, Tuesday?
-不是明年七月嗎  -不  星期二
- Not next July? - No. Tuesday.
-你的聽力還好嗎  -不
- Is your hearing all right? - No.
不  我的聽力很好  只是你一直在說
No, my hearing is fine, it's just, you keep saying
很多很奇怪的事情
lots of really strange things.
但是我加入  是的  謝謝
But yes, yes, thank you, yes.
-你需要多長時間  -大約30分鐘  最多
- Um, how long do you need? - About 30 minutes. Maximum.
如果再多的話  人們就開始不安了
Any more than that, people start getting a bit restless.
-你知道的  "快上主菜吧"  -是啊
- You know, "Bring on the ginger geezer." - Yeah.
找到了
Get in.
晚安
Night.
-晚安  -晚安
- Night. - Night.
晚安  很高興認識你
Night. Nice to meet you.
你看起來有點像艾德·希蘭  你知道嗎
You look like Ed Sheeran, you know.
我就是艾德·希蘭
I am Ed Sheeran.
是啊  演的真好
Oh, right. Well done.
要燈光表演嗎
Light show?
-最好不要  不  -很好
- Preferably not, no. - Well, that's good,
因為我只有手機手電筒  所以
'cause I've only got the torch on my phone, so...
你有啤酒嗎
Have you got any beer?
有蘋果酒
Uh, cider.
-蘋果酒也行  -好的
- Cider works. - Okay.
我要和寫了《昨天》的人喝杯蘋果酒了
I'll have a cider with the man that wrote "Yesterday."
是啊
Yeah.
媽媽  爸爸  誰把蘋果酒都喝了
Mum, Dad, who drunk all the cider?
-真是瘋了  -是的  就像你說的  很瘋狂
- That is nuts! - Yeah, as you said, it's nutty.
他全身都是紋身
And he's absolutely covered in tattoos.
順便說一句  睡衣很漂亮
Nice dressing gown, by the way.
不  不漂亮  不
No, it's not. No.
不要  別說
Don't. Don't start.
網上看起來很不錯  所以我就買了
It looked so good online, so I just ordered it,
然後歷史上最噁心的粉紅色就出現了
and the most disgusting pink thing in history turns up.
-真好  -同時  你需要一個新司機
- So good. - Meanwhile, you need a new roadie.
明天
Tomorrow.
你什麼意思  你不來了
What do you mean? You're not coming?
不  當然不去
No, of course not.
我  你知道  是個教師
I'm, you know, a schoolteacher.
我教數學
I teach maths.
我不能突然管理上
I can't suddenly manage
艾德·希蘭的支援演出了
Ed Sheeran's support act.
或許你可以
Yeah, maybe you can, though.
是啊
Um... yeah.
不過這個星期二肯定不行
Well, I certainly can't do it this Tuesday.
因為我們6點45分有個家長會
'Cause we've got a parent- teacher's evening at 6:45.
儘管我喜歡你  我
And, although I like you, I...
但還沒到為了你讓整個十年級失望的程度
I don't like you enough to let down the whole of year ten.
是的  好吧  對不起
Right. Okay. Sorry.
露西  艾莉辭職了
Lucy, Ellie's resigned from her post.
你想星期二在莫斯科做我的旅伴嗎
Do you fancy being my roadie in Moscow on Tuesday?
對不起  很樂意
Sorry. Would love to,
但我們有校劇的排練
but we've got rehearsals for the school play.
好吧
- Mm-hmm. Okay.
讓我們想想  C計畫
Let's think, plan C.
-糟了  -什麼
- Oh, no. - What?
我有個主意  但是個很壞的主意
I've had an idea. It's a very bad idea.
♪ 我淪陷於你無比美妙的身體 ♪
♪ I'm in love with your body ♪
♪ 深陷其中  無法自拔 ♪
你好
Hi.
♪ 我深陷在你名妝的愛裡 ♪
♪ I'm in love with the shape of you. ♪
歡迎登機
Welcome aboard. - Hey. Oh. - Hey.
你好嗎  夥計
How you doing, man? Hey!
久仰大名
Here he is. Hey.
你好  希蘭先生  我叫洛基
Hello, Mr. Sheeran. My name's Rocky.
你隨意怎麼叫我
And y-you can call me whatever you like.
"帥哥"總是挺不錯的
"Handsome" always works well.
不
No.
只是開玩笑  不  洛基  洛基就好
Only kidding, no, it was just... Rock... just call me Rocky.
-很高興見到你  洛基  -是啊
- Nice to meet you, Rocky. - Yeah.
傑克  你和洛基的座位在後面
Um, Jack, you and Rocky are at the back there.
聽著  今晚的演出很小很親密
And listen, um, tonight, it's small and intimate.
別擔心  沒什麼好擔心的
Don't worry. Nothing to be worried about.
-好的  可以  -好的
- Okay. Cool. - All right.
-很喜歡你的作品  夥計  -謝謝
- Love your work, man. - Thank you.
-尤其是說唱  -真的嗎
- Especially the rapping. - Really?
不  我只是開玩笑
No, I'm only kidding.
不  交給兄弟們唱吧  這是我的建議
No, leave it to the brothers, that'd be my advice.
金格和饒舌結合  聽起來有點垃圾
Gingers and rap... sounds a bit crap.
你可能沒錯  旅途好好坐
Well, you may be right. Enjoy your flight.
開始了嗎
Oh, here he is.
稍等
Wait a minute!
好的
All right, um...
機上坐下  整潔無話
uh, I think it will be neat if I take my seat.
完勝
Boom. Victory.
準備飛往
Gonna fly to the...
香檳要嗎
Champagne?
是的  拜託  謝謝你
Oh, yes, please. Thank you.
香檳嗎  先生
Champagne, sir?
你有可樂嗎
Um, have you got Coke?
抱歉
Sorry?
是的  請給我百事
Oh, right, yeah. Pepsi, please.
當然  先生
Of course, sir.
♪ 重返蘇聯 ♪
♪ Back in the US, back in the US ♪
♪ Back in the USSR ♪
莫     斯     科
♪ 烏克蘭女孩們把我搞得一臉懵逼 ♪
♪ Well, the Ukraine girls really knock me out ♪
♪ 他們把西方拋在身後 ♪
♪ They leave the West behind ♪
♪ 莫斯科女孩們讓我歌唱呐喊 ♪
♪ And the Moscow girls make me sing and shout ♪
♪ 佐治亞一直在我的腦海裡 ♪
♪ Georgia's always on my mi-mi-mi-mi-mi-mi-mi-mi-mind ♪
好的  莫斯科
All right, Moscow!
和我一起唱吧
Sing it with me!
大聲點
Louder than that!
Louder!
♪ 重返蘇聯 ♪
♪ Back in the USSR ♪
♪ 你不知道自己有多幸運  孩子們 ♪
♪ You don't know how lucky you are, boys ♪
♪ 重返蘇聯 ♪
♪ Back in the USSR. ♪
謝謝
Cheers.
好的  莫斯科
Okay, Moscow,
感謝傑克·馬利卡
it was Jack Malik!
現在你準備好了嗎
And now are you ready
迎接艾德·希蘭了嗎
for Ed Sheeran?!
沒有吉他  三小時飛機上寫出來的
On a three-hour plane journey, without a guitar?
是啊
Yeah.
因為我想著我們要去俄羅斯
'Cause I thought we were going to Russia,
所以我應該寫一首關於俄羅斯的歌
so I should write a song about Russia.
是的  我只是覺得你
Yeah, that... I just, I thought it was really cool
用"蘇聯"一詞很酷  你知道嗎
that you called it "USSR," you know?
在你出生之前
It probably stopped being called that
可能就不叫這個了
before you were born.
是啊
Yeah.
真是神奇  哥們
Amazing, man.
-很喜歡那個USSR音樂  -謝謝
- Loved that USSR track. - Thanks.
對了  我有個想法
Right. I've got an idea.
大家好  我覺得大家都一致認為
Everyone, I think we can all agree that we're impressed
傑克的寫歌天賦  對吧
with Jack's songwriting talent, right?
所以我有個計畫
So, here's the plan.
我會從那扇門出來  傑克從這扇門出來
I'm gonna go out that door, Jack's gonna go out this door.
誰在十分鐘內寫出的歌最好誰贏
And whoever writes the best song in ten minutes, wins.
獎品是什麼
What's the prize?
沒有獎品  只是被認為是最好的作曲家
No prize. Just being the best songwriter.
傑克·重返蘇聯·馬利卡  你要來嗎
Jack "Back in the USSR" Malik, are you in?
-行  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
不能寫你之前寫過的歌
And it can't be anything you've written before.
拿出你的看家本領
Like, nothing in your bottom drawer.
必須要是新的歌  今晚完成
Has to be new, tonight.
-行  -好
- Right. - Cool.
-有意思  -我還是
- Fun. - I still,
還是認為要有個獎品  艾德
still think there should be a prize, Ed.
我是說  他的所有身家能有個十磅
I mean, with all his money, he could afford a tenner.
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
我們今晚將見證這場史詩級的比賽
we are gathered here tonight to witness an epic battle.
藍方是
In the blue corner,
艾德·希蘭爵士
Sir Ed Sheeran!
♪ 心碎的人總能在某處找到 ♪
♪ Broken hearts can find a love to make them whole ♪
♪ 另一半 ♪
♪ Anywhere ♪
♪ 她說我們是冰上的企鵝 ♪
♪ She said we are penguins on the ice ♪
♪ 註定無法飛翔  但我們總要嘗試 ♪
♪ We're not meant to fly, but God knows we can try ♪
♪ 我在你眼中看到希望 ♪
♪ Well, I see a hope that's in your eyes ♪
♪ 你能看到我眼中的愛意嗎 ♪
♪ Well, can you see the love in mine? ♪
現在輪到
And now,
必輸無疑的  傑克·馬利卡先生
the soon-to-be defeated, Mr. Jack Malik!
♪ 大風呼嘯的漫漫長路 ♪
♪ The long and winding road ♪
♪ 引我走向你心門 ♪
♪ That leads to your door ♪
♪ 永不消失 ♪
♪ Will never disappear ♪
♪ 我曾走過這路 ♪
♪ I've seen that road before ♪
♪ 它總引我來到這 ♪
♪ It always leads me here ♪
♪ 引我來到你心門 ♪
♪ Lead me to your door ♪
♪ 多少次我孤身一人 ♪
♪ Many times I've been alone ♪
♪ 多少次我放聲大哭 ♪
♪ And many times I've cried ♪
♪ 無論如何你都不會知道 ♪
♪ Any way you'll never know ♪
♪ 我曾試過多少辦法 ♪
♪ The many ways I've tried ♪
♪ 但它們總是引我回到 ♪
♪ But still they lead me back ♪
♪ 回到大風呼嘯 ♪
♪ To the long ♪
♪ 的漫漫長路 ♪
♪ And winding road ♪
♪ 你留下我一人 ♪
♪ You left me standing here ♪
♪ 在多少年以前 ♪
♪ A long, long time ago ♪
♪ 別讓我在這一直等待 ♪
♪ Don't leave me waiting here ♪
♪ 引我走向你心門 ♪
♪ Lead me to your door. ♪
來吧  投票
So, the vote!
不  不投票  不用投了
Nope, no vote. No vote.
那真是個有意思的時刻
No. That was, uh, an interesting moment.
總有人和我說你會遇到
I was always told that there would be someone
一個比你更厲害的人
who came along that was a lot better than me,
傑克  你的確比我厲害
and you are definitely better than me, Jack.
不得不承認  那真是
Yeah, wow. That was, uh,
我人生中聽過的最動聽的歌曲之一
one of the best songs I've heard in my life.
我想說  這些東西很複雜
I mean, these things are complicated.
是啊
Yeah.
但顯然對你來說不複雜  是嗎
Obviously not complicated for you, though, right?
我想去睡覺了
I think I'm gonna go to bed.
有機會的妹子們一定要睡他
Someone should probably shag him while they have the chance.
-是的  -選我  傑克
- Yeah. - Pick me, Jack!
你絕對是莫札特轉世  哥們
You're definitely Mozart, mate.
我絕對是薩利埃裡
And I'm definitely Salieri.
薩利埃裡vs莫札特  人物關係大致等同于周瑜vs諸葛亮
晚安  傑克
Night, Jack.
你好  我叫黛布拉·漢莫
Hi. I'm Debra Hammer.
我是艾德的經紀人
I'm Ed's manager.
我們得聊聊
We should talk.
好  我  我得  我是說
Yeah. I... Well, I g... I mean,
我已經有經紀人了
I've kind of got a manager back home. Oh?
不  不過  我們的確該聊聊
No, but, but no, but we should talk.
-行  -好的  很好  那很好
- Yeah. - Okay, great. That's great.
好吧
Uh... good.
祝你好夢  我們洛杉磯見
Have a good night. I'll see you in Los Angeles.
洛杉磯
In Los Angeles?
是的  我們需要你去一趟洛杉磯
Yeah, well, we, we need you to come to L.A.
聽著  我們付錢讓你來寫歌
See, we pay and then you come and you write songs
然後我們將它們發佈  你會得到很多錢
and then we release them, and you make a ton of money.
我們會從中抽走大部分錢
And then we take most of it.
好  我有個問題問你
Okay. I have a question.
這是你能打扮的最帥的樣子了嗎
Is this the best that you can look?
我們會解決的
We'll figure it out.
唱得真好
Gorgeous.
艾莉  艾莉  艾莉
Ellie, Ellie, Ellie!
在我作為傑克的
Oh, well, in my capacity as Jack's
薩福克
前音樂指導  兼任經紀人
former musical mentor, stroke manager,
技術人員  還有司機
stroke roadie, stroke driver...
因為他連開車都不會
'Cause he can't even drive.
廢柴  廢柴
Ooh! Loser! Loser!
我確實有努力教你
I did try to teach you. I did try to teach you.
-說實話  你可以回來工作  -不要
- Honestly, no, you can have the job back. - No, thanks.
為什麼會有人不為薩福克
Why would anyone ever leave Suffolk
奉獻終生呢
before the day they die?
好了  但如果你一定要去洛杉磯
Right, but if you must go to Los Angeles
-和妓女還有癮君子一起玩  -我得去
- and hang out with perverts and drug addicts... - I must.
那我們祝你好運  馬到成功
...then we wish you good luck and success.
或者  失敗  然後趕緊回來更好
Or, even better, failure and a swift return.
祝你失敗然後趕緊回來
Failure and a swift return!
傑克  你會想我嗎
Will you miss me, Jack?
當然會想你字幕
Course I'll miss you. Hey.
我當然會想你
Of course I'll miss you.
你要走了  所以  我可以要求任何事
You're leaving, so... I can ask you anything.
我是怎麼被劃到錯誤的這一欄裡的呢
How did I get in the wrong column?
我是怎麼被劃到
How did I get in
"朋友  經紀人  技術人員"這欄
the "friend, manager, roadie" column, inst...
而不是"我也愛她"這一欄的呢
...instead of the "And I Love Her" column?
你上去幹嘛呢
What are you doing up there?
快點  如果你不趕緊下樓
Come on. If you don't come downstairs soon,
你媽就要喝醉開始長篇大論了
your mum will be too drunk to make her speech.
-傑克  -走吧  小艾莉
- Jack! - Coming, Ellie Wellie?
-好  -快下來  寶貝  我們想你
- Yeah. - Come on down, my baby bunny, we miss you!
-傑克  -艾莉
- Jack! - Ellie!
-傑克  -傑克
- Jack! -Jack!
傑克  你在上面幹什麼呢
Jackie, what are you doing up there?
我真的需要把你歸到某一欄嗎
Oh, God. Are those definitely columns?
傑克
Jack!
女生當然可以分辨的清楚
Well, a girl can certainly tell the difference.
-傑克  -這
- Jack! - It...
事實上  說真的  情況有些不妙
Actually, seriously, it is getting a bit grim,
所以你還是快下樓吧
so you may wanna, uh, uh, come down.
-快點  -我們想你
- Come on! - We miss you!
傑克
Jack!
艾莉  那真是
Wow, Ellie. That's...
-這個重要的晚上裡的大新聞啊  -艾莉
- big news on a big night. - Ellie!
傑克  趕緊下來  哥們
Jack, get down here now, mate!
傑克
Jack!
快點
Come on!
傑克  傑克  傑克  傑克
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack...
傑克
Jack!
洛 杉 磯
♪ 太陽出來了 ♪
♪ Here comes the sun ♪
♪ 太陽出來了  我說 ♪
♪ Here comes the sun, and I say ♪
♪ 沒事了放心吧 ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
接住了
Get it!
♪ 太陽啊太陽 ♪
♪ Sun, sun, sun ♪
♪ 它出來了 ♪
♪ Here it comes ♪
♪ 太陽啊太陽  它出來了 ♪
♪ Sun, sun, sun, here it comes ♪
-這條街有很好吃的素食餐廳  -女士
- ...cute vegan place down the street, I love it. - Ladies.
♪ 太陽啊太陽  它出來了 ♪
♪ Sun, sun, sun, here it comes. ♪
傑克·馬利卡
Jack Malik.
歡迎光臨寒舍
Welcome to my little beach shack.
感謝你一路趕來
Thank you for coming all this way.
很高興見到你
Good to see you. Well...
-你並不是很迷人  -沒錯
- you're not very attractive. - No.
-而且身材走樣  -是的
- You're out of shape. - Yes.
你骨瘦如柴  但不知怎的  卻很圓
You're skinny, yet, somehow, round.
十年來了你一直很不成功
You have been profoundly unsuccessful for ten years.
-是的  -直到一個月以前
- Yep. - And until about a month ago,
我們都會說你是徹底的失敗者
we'd call you a complete failure.
我不會這麼說  但是
Well, that's not quite how I'd put it, but...
-我們會說你是個徹底的失敗者  -是
- We would say that you were a complete failure. - Yeah.
請坐
Sit, please.
但現在  此刻
But now, now...
你的歌寫的很棒
you've hit an extraordinary songwriting groove,
同時你想要成為世界巨星
and you want to be the biggest star in the world.
-其實  -只要回答"是"就行了
- Well, mmm... - "Yes" is the answer to that question.
我想是的
Well, yes, I guess.
不是"我想是的"
Not, "Well, yes, I guess."
說"是的"
"Yes."
我猜
I guess.
夥計  我提供給你的
Buddy, what I'm offering you,
是偉大光榮的金錢與名譽
is the great and glorious poisoned chalice
的毒酒
of money and fame.
如果你不想要
If you don't want to drink it,
我能理解
which I would understand,
回你那小小快樂的英國喝啤酒去吧
go back and have a warm beer in little, bonny England.
如果你想要
If you do want to drink it,
我需要你說"黛布拉  我饑渴難耐
I need to hear you say, "Debra, I'm so thirsty.
快給我這該死的酒"
Give me the goddamn chalice."
所以  你的選擇是
So, which is it?
這酒我幹了
I'll take the chalice.
好
Yeah.
♪ 你問我我的愛會與日俱增嗎 ♪
♪ You're asking me will my love grow ♪
♪ 我不知道 ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ I... don't know ♪
♪ 你留下  一切都會見分曉 ♪
♪ Stick around now, it may show ♪
♪ 我不知道 ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ I... don't know. ♪
好  我感受到了
Yeah. I'm feeling that.
好了  下一首是什麼
Okay, what's next?
這首歌叫《疲憊之夜》
Um, it's called "A Hard Day's Night."
好的
All right.
意思是什麼呢
What does that mean?
我還不清楚
Um, I'm not quite sure yet.
好吧  你準備好之後我們就開始
Okay, we're rolling when you're ready.
停  停下  少了什麼
Stop, stop. Something's missing.
吉他  吉他得再柔和些
It-it's the guitar, it has to gently weep more.
就是這樣  我的寶貝
That's it! That's my baby!
-是的  棒  -是嗎  好
- Yes! Yes! - Yeah? Good.
♪ 我要唱起夏日之歌 ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing this summer song ♪
♪ 我要唱完一整個夏天 ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing all summer long. ♪
-好  第一首個  -《太陽升起》
- Okay. The first one... - "Here Comes the Sun."
是  對  沒錯  很棒
Is... Yeah, yeah. That's amazing.
-第二首  -我個人最喜歡的歌
- And the second one... - My personal favorite.
-《夏日戀歌》  -《夏日戀歌》
- "The Summer Song." - "The Summer Song."
那是
That is...
很簡單但是不吸引人
it's simple without being charming.
很難找到一個合適的詞語來形容
I'm struggling to find the words.
我不喜歡  但是
I hated it, but n...
我沒興趣再聽一遍
I wasn't interested in it enough to listen to it again
來找原因
to find out why.
是的  別管它了
Yeah, bin it.
是的  不要這個了
Yeah. Reject.
謝謝你  洛基
Thank you, Rocky.
我真希望時間都能像現在這樣
Times like this, I wish
我還沒有戒煙
I hadn't given up smoking.
我可以幹掉一根煙
I could just murder a cigarette.
是啊
Yeah.
什麼是cigarette
What's a "cigarette"?
什麼
What?
哇
Wow.
對了  傑克  這是希拉蕊
Uh... oh, yes, Jack, this is Hilary.
她是你的造型師
She's gonna be working with you on your image.
我必須要有造型嗎
Do I have to have an image?
對  如果你沒有的話
Well, if you don't have an image,
那麼形象不好將會是個問題
then the lack of image becomes an image. Right.
音樂那麼好聽
And the music sounds so joyful.
如果因你這個樣子而拖了好音樂的後腿
It'd be a shame to let it down by you being so...
-那會很遺憾  -嗯嗯
- off-putting. - Mm-hmm.
我能看出為什麼你們兩個會成為朋友
I can see how you two might be friends.
對
Yeah, yeah.
那麼  接下來  計畫是這樣的
So, here... Okay, here's the plan.
我們將會選出五首最好的歌曲
We're gonna take the five best songs,
把它們放在網上  對吧
we'll put them online, right?
沒有視覺效果  只有音樂
No visuals, just the music.
神秘的傑克·馬利卡
The enigma of Jack Malik.
然後我們等到
And then, we wait until we've...
解決你的形象問題
fixed all of this,
我們會發佈
and we release
震驚歌壇
an astonishing,
定義時代的雙專輯
era-defining double album
永遠地改變流行樂壇
that changes popular music forever.
♪ 男孩  你將承受這一切 ♪
♪ Boy, you're gonna carry that weight ♪
♪ 長時間承受這一切 ♪
♪ Carry that weight a long time ♪
♪ 男孩  你將承受這一切 ♪
♪ Boy, you're gonna carry that weight ♪
♪ 長時間承受這一切 ♪
♪ Carry that weight a long time ♪
傑克·馬利卡
# JackMalik.
她愛你
# SheLovesYou.
我一直知道他是明星  從一開始就知道
I always knew he was a star, right from the start.
在早些時候我們不分上下
We were very much neck and neck in the earlier days.
我們都是歌手
We were both entertainers.
《昨日》
"Yesterday."
我說更多歌迷  我說傑克
Me say more fans. Me say Jacko!
加文是著名倉庫磁帶的製作者
The producer of the now-famous "Warehouse Tapes," Gavin.
當然是我人生中最精彩的瞬間
Absolutely and utterly the, the best moment of my life.
總的來說  我們總是談論
Basically, we seem to be talking
流行樂壇的莎士比亞
about the Shakespeare of pop music.
這些歌曲  只有其中五首
These songs, there's only five of them,
它們開闢了新天地  我們以前沒聽過
but they break new ground. We've never heard
像這樣的歌曲
anything like this before.
我們想要更多  我們當然需要更多
We want more. But we definitely need to hear more.
更多  寫更多的新歌曲  傑克
More songs. More, more... Write more new songs, Jack.
毋庸置疑這是最好的唱片
The best album ever. No question.
♪ 埃莉諾·瑞格 坐在教堂裡 ♪
♪ Eleanor Rigby, sits in the church ♪
♪ 晚上的婚禮在哪裡 ♪
♪ In the night where the wedding has been... ♪
不
No.
♪ 看她正在工作 ♪
♪ Look at her working ♪
♪ 晚上正在織她的襪子時 ♪
♪ Darning her socks in the night when the... ♪
那兒有米粒
There's rice in there, somewhere.
撿起米粒  撿起米粒 撿起米粒
Picks up the rice, picks up the rice, picks up the rice.
♪ 撿起教堂裡的米粒 ♪
♪ Picks up the rice in the church ♪
♪ 婚禮在哪裡舉行 ♪
♪ Where a wedding has been ♪
♪ 活在夢中 ♪
♪ Lives in a dream ♪
她到底在哪裡織襪子
Where does she darn the bloody socks?
麥肯錫神父  麥肯錫神父
Father McKenzie, Father McKenzie!
♪ 麥肯錫神父  在晚上織襪子 ♪
♪ Father McKenzie, darning his socks in the night ♪
♪ 織襪子  織 ♪
♪ Darning his socks... Dar... ♪
天呐
Oh, God.
我們什麼時候到  所有孤獨的人
When are we gonna get to "all the lonely people"?
♪ 所有孤獨的人 ♪
♪ All the lonely people ♪
♪ 他們都在哪裡 ♪
♪ Where do they all c... ♪
我需要馬上去利物浦
I need to go to Liverpool as soon as possible.
我想那能夠激發我的靈感
I think it could be inspiring.
你想讓我告訴你世界上比利物浦
Do you want me to tell you the name of 50 places on Earth
更能激發靈感的50個地方嗎
more inspiring than Liverpool?
-從美國的斯泰茨維爾開始  -不  謝謝
- Starting with Shitsville, USA. - No, thank you.
你想知道你這周為什麼
Would you like me to tell you
不能去的原因嗎
the reasons that you can't go next week?
因為要和環球音樂的總監歐尼斯特吃午飯
Like having lunch with Ernesto, the head of Universal Music,
你這輩子就靠他了
on whom your life depends.
因為要完成這張該死的專輯
Like actually finishing the damn album.
因為要給這該死的專輯起一個名字
Like picking the damn name for the damn album.
還因為要給這該死的專輯做MV  該死
Like doing the damn videos for the damn album, damn it.
好了  我週六之前回來
Okay, I will be back by Saturday.
週五
Friday!
週五是你和詹姆斯·柯登的深夜秀
Friday is you on The Late Late Show with James Corden.
週六是重點市場行銷會議
And Saturday is the Major Marketing Meeting of Meetings.
週五  你就要被推到鏡頭前
Friday, you are presented to the world.
週六  就是你加冕的日子
Saturday, you are crowned.
好  那就週五
Okay, Friday.
真的叫重點市場行銷會議
Is it actually called "the Major Marketing Meeting  of Meetings"?
是的  真這麼叫
Yes, it's actually called that.
沒錯
Yes.
利物浦有什麼洛杉磯沒有的嗎
What does Liverpool have that L.A. doesn't?
像莫·薩拉赫  茜拉·布萊克
Mo Salah, Cilla Black,
莫·薩拉赫: 利物浦球星  茜拉·布萊克: 利物浦歌手
豌豆糊  還有下不完的雨
mushy peas, rain.
終於到家了
Home sweet home.
洛基  你又不是來自利物浦的
Rocky, you're not from Liverpool, mate.
不是  從來沒來過
Nope. Never been here before.
傑克  傑克
Hey, Jack, Jack!
天呐
Oh. Oh, my God.
傑克
Jack!
他們怎麼知道我們在這裡的
H-How did they know we were here?
快快  進去  快點
In, in, in. Drive, drive! Come on.
天呐  這是
Oh, my God, it's...
等一下傑克  為什麼不停下
Wait, Jack! Why won't you stop, mate?
到地方了  草莓地
There you go, guys, Strawberry Field.
♪ 讓我帶你下來 ♪
♪ Let me take you down ♪
現在我們在便士小巷
Now we're at Penny Lane.
這和其他小巷有什麼區別嗎
What distinguishes it from any other lane?
放尊敬點
Just show some respect.
憑什麼
For what, exactly?
還有埃莉諾·瑞格
"Also Eleanor Rigby,
湯瑪斯·伍茲的愛妻
the beloved wife of Thomas Woods." Yeah?
摯友  親人
Friend? Relative? Wh...
♪ 埃莉諾·瑞格 ♪
♪ Eleanor Rigby... ♪
我一直很喜歡墓地
I always liked graveyards.
我的第一次就是在墓地裡
Lost my virginity in one, actually.
♪ 所有孤獨的人 ♪
♪ All the lonely people ♪
♪ 他們屬於哪裡 ♪
♪ Where do they all belong? ♪
♪ 埃莉諾·瑞格 ♪
♪ Eleanor Rigby ♪
♪ 撿起教堂裡的米粒 ♪
♪ Picks up the rice in the church ♪
♪ 婚禮在哪裡舉行 ♪
♪ Where the wedding has been ♪
對
Yes!
♪ 活在夢中 ♪
♪ Lives in a dream ♪
♪ 麥肯錫神父 在寫東西 ♪
♪ Father McKenzie, writing the words ♪
♪ 一個沒有人會聽到的說教 ♪
♪ Of a sermon that no one will hear ♪
♪ 沒有人來 ♪
♪ No one comes near ♪
天呐  火力全開
Oh, come on, he's on fire!
消防員
Fireman!
便士小巷裡有一個消防員
There's a fireman in "Penny Lane."
天啊
Jesus!
什麼
What?
-什麼  -很抱歉打擾你  但是樓下
- What? - I'm sorry to disturb you, but you've got
-有人找你  -真的嗎  誰
- someone downstairs for you. - What, really?
你在這兒幹什麼
What are you doing here?
我只是經過這兒而已
I was just passing by.
你住在370英里外
You live 370 miles away.
好吧 你對了
Yeah, you're right. Um...
我只是
I just...
我只是  我想見你一面比較好
I just, I thought it might be nice to see you.
那你在這裡幹什麼
What are you doing here? Um...
我在做研究
well, it's research.
搞搞音樂事業什麼的
It's, like, a music industry thing. Yeah.
太好了
This is so great.
你餓了嗎
Are you hungry?
-能吃下一頭牛  -那走吧
- As a big horse. - Okay.
感覺你好像永遠離開了
Oh, it feels like you've been gone forever.
尼克和卡羅爾怎麼樣
How are Nick and Carol?
-很不開心  -太好了
- Very unhappy. - Excellent.
他們真的相處融洽的話我不知道怎麼辦
I wouldn't know how to relate to 'em if they actually got on.
我很想你
I miss you.
我也很想你
And I miss you.
是的
Yes.
我想要炸魚和薯條
I am gonna have fish and chips.
但是我在減肥
But I'm on a diet.
所以換沙拉吧
So, salad instead of the fries.
我還是要烤鮭魚
I'll have the grilled salmon, and again,
也要沙拉  不要薯條
with a salad, no fries.
還要其他的嗎
Anything else?
要一份薯條吧
Maybe just a side of fries.
好  兩份  在多來點啤酒  謝謝
Yeah, make that two. And lots more beers. Thanks.
我猜女孩們會為了和你睡而灌醉自己
I guess the girls are falling over themselves
現在你是一個出名的音樂家
to sleep with you, now you're a famous musician?
我不出名  不  還沒有
I'm not famous. And no, not yet.
儘管有一個俄羅斯女孩
Although there was one Russian.
那很不錯  她胖嗎
That's nice. Was she stocky?
對 很胖
Fairly stocky, yeah.
-酒吧要關門了還需要什麼嗎  -不了
- Bar's closing. Can I get you anything else? - No, thanks.
來幾杯白蘭地吧
Maybe just a couple of brandies.
多來點巧克力
And lots of chocolates.
他們把我們趕出去怎麼辦
What are we gonna do when they throw us out?
我也在想  多帶點克他命
I was thinking... lots of ketamine.
然後  在利物浦的大街上散步
Mmm. And then, wandering the streets
唱著不知道歌詞的歌曲
of Liverpool, singing songs we don't know the lyrics of.
很大聲
Very loudly.
你變了
You've changed.
你好
Hello?
你的房間在哪裡
So, where's your room?
當然不在這層
Oh, definitely, definitely not on this floor.
漫長的停頓
Long pause. Yeah.
我搞砸了嗎
Have I messed up massively?
-什麼意思  -離開
- Meaning what? - Going away, and...
沒有  當然沒有
Oh, no. God, no.
不然你會怎麼選呢
What was the alternative?
這可是世界上最令人激動的事
This is the most wonderful and exciting thing in the world.
我能把燈關了嗎
Can I maybe turn out the light?
可以
Maybe.
會不會是個錯誤
Mistake?
也許吧
Probably.
天呐  你剛剛摸了我的屁股
Oh, my God, you just... you touched my bottom.
你以前從沒這麼做過
You've never done that before.
我想我們馬上還要做
Well, I imagine we're gonna have to do
很多以前沒做過的事情
a lot of things we've never done before.
你確定要做嗎
Are you sure?
-那你呢  -我先問的
- And what about you? - I asked first.
我確實不清楚
I really don't know.
好了  我知道了
Oh, okay.
所以  答案也許是不
So, maybe no.
不
No?
這次到利物浦這裡來確實不是個錯誤
It's certainly not a mistake coming up to Liverpool.
這也確實是一個美好的夜晚
Certainly, um, a lovely evening.
但是我覺得  也許  再
But I think, probably, it's...
-再進一步就錯了  -好吧
- it's a mistake to go further. - Okay.
我自己有房間而且
I have a room of my own and...
而且我覺得
and I think, um...
成為你一夜情佇列裡的人
a one-night stand would be...
對我來說很奇怪  傑克
a strange new column for me to be in, Jack.
也許這  這並不會是一夜情
Maybe it, it wouldn't be a one-night stand.
那你什麼時候飛回美國
Well, when are you going back to America?
-明天  -所以這就是一夜情
- Tomorrow. - So that's one night.
這就是字典裡一夜情的標準定義
It's the dictionary definition of a one-night stand and...
這並不是我想要的
it's not for me.
♪ 我說也許 ♪
♪ I said maybe ♪
樂隊爭霸賽
♪ 我註定唯你所依 ♪
♪ You're gonna be the one that saves me ♪
♪ 因為畢竟 ♪
♪ And after all ♪
♪ 你是我命中的奇跡 ♪
♪ You're my wonderwall... ♪
洛基
Rocky!
洛基  快起床
Rocky! Get up.
-我們要走了  -啥  怎麼了
- Let's go! - What? What? What?
我們得去找艾莉
We've gotta find Ellie!
-我知道她在哪  -在哪
- I know where she is. - Where?
-在薩福克  老兄  -不  她不在
- In Suffolk, mate. - No, she's not,
她就在利物浦  你個鐵憨憨
she's in Liverpool, you numpty.
真的嗎  那可太巧了
Really? That's a coincidence.
我們
Uh, we...
你這裡有客人叫艾莉·埃普敦嗎
You have got a guest, Ellie Appleton.
是的  我們剛幫她叫了輛
Oh, yeah, we just ordered her
去火車站的計程車
a taxi to the station.
蒼天啊
Oh, Christ.
非常感謝
Uh, thank you very much.
-好  -不不不  好吧
- Okay. - No, no, no. Okay.
咱分頭找  你往那邊走  我往這邊走
Double our chances... you go that way, I'll go this way.
-不管誰先找到她  攔住她  -好的
- Whoever gets there first, stops her. - Okay.
你在這啊  是往那邊  是往那邊
Oh, there you are. It's that way. It's that way.
萊姆街火車站
累死我了
I'm dying.
艾莉  艾爾  老天啊
Ellie. Elle. Oh, my God.
萊姆街火車站
我希望她值得我們追  老兄
I hope she's worth it, mate.
這要往哪
Where's the...?
請問有人知道去倫敦的月臺是幾號嗎
D-Does anyone know what platform goes to London?
-六號  -八號
- Six. - Eight.
不  絕對是六號
No, it's definitely six.
對  我錯了  是六號
Oh, yeah, no, it's six.
確實是六號  不好意思
It's definitely six. Sorry.
好  好  好
Yes, yes, yes!
別別別  別走  該死
No, no, no, no, no, no!
別這樣
No. No.
快點  快接  快接
Come on, pick up. Pick up.
-喂  -喂  好
- Hello? - Hi, yes.
我  我來追你了
I-I came after you,
但我沒趕上車
but I missed the train.
對不起
I'm sorry.
-我們要談一談  -來談吧
- We need to talk. - Let's talk.
-你在哪裡  -就在你身後
- Where are you? - Right behind you.
我點了份番茄芝士法棍
Having a cheese and tomato baguette
和一袋薯片
and a packet of crisps.
傑克  如果我現在要說
Jack, would it, would it be
我們要去機場了  會不會是
annoying of me to point out we should be
-火上澆油  -我們還有多少時間
- heading for the airport? - How long have we got?
實際來算  不到一個小時
Well, in real terms, minus an hour.
好了
Okay.
洛基  這場交談完全與你無關
Rocky, this is completely not a conversation you're part of.
-對  當然無關  -對
- No, of course it's not. - Yeah.
對  非常私人
No, deeply private.
事關你未來的幸福
With your future happiness at stake.
對了  你們昨晚睡了沒
Right, did you two sleep together last night?
-沒有  -沒有  -真是浪費機會啊
- No. - No. - What a waste.
不管了  我會看著時間
Anyway, I'll keep an eye on the clock.
你們還有剛好四分鐘時間
You've got precisely four minutes.
-那麼  -那麼
- So... - So...
我想講下昨天晚上的事
it's about last night.
怎麼說
What about it?
昨晚有那麼一刻
Well, it was almost quite a moment.
我醒過來  六神無主  就想找你談談
And I woke up, and I panicked. And I wanted to talk.
好的  那就說吧
Okay, then talk.
好吧
Right.
所以
So, um...
因為我們
N... 'cause we...
所以你覺得現在是什麼情況
And how do you think it's going so far?
情況不太妙  但是
It's not great, but...
不不  讓我來試著幫你說吧
No, no, let me try and help.
你有二十年的時間能向我表白
You've had 20 years to make your move.
我七歲的時候肯定沒法表白
Well, I couldn't exactly make my move when I was seven.
那就算你十年吧
Then you've had ten years.
對  但我們一直都像兄弟姐妹一樣
Right. Well, we've always been like brother and sister.
兄弟姐妹做愛
It's very bad indeed for...
是一件非常離譜的事請
for brothers and sisters to have sex.
然而我們並不是兄弟姐妹
Except that we're not brother and sister.
確實不是  對  但是
No, exactly. Right, but...
不是  所以
No, so...
我等了你半輩子
I've been waiting half my life
希望你對我的愛能覺醒
for you to wake up and love me.
愛了你半輩子時間
Having loved you for half a lifetime,
我才意識到你走的時候
I realized when you left,
我那麼做是個多麼錯誤的決定
that I had made a bad choice doing that.
而現在  事情更加複雜了  因為
And now, it's got even trickier because...
在酒吧玩的時候  我們真是天作之合
When you were playing in pubs, we were the perfect match.
但現在
But now...
我
I-i...
我實際上就是個洛斯托夫特的學校老師
I'm an actual schoolteacher in actual Lowestoft,
而你是  世界上最有名的原創歌手
and you're the world's greatest singer-songwriter.
-不  我不是  -然而你可能就是
- No, I'm not. - Except that you probably are.
好了  兩分鐘  老爺太太  兩分鐘
Okay. Two minutes, ladies and gentlemen, two minutes.
另外  黛布拉打我的電話來催你了
Also, um... Debra's on my phone for you.
很顯然  她正在和唱片公司老總吃飯
Apparently, she's having dinner with the head of the label
並且正在FaceTime上找你
and you're meant to be FaceTiming in, so...
視頻通話軟體
一邊去  洛基
Just go away, Rocky.
好的  還有1分53秒
Okay. One minute, 53.
到最後  對你而言
In the end, to you,
我永遠就是那個卷髮女生艾莉
I'll always, really, just be Ellie with the frizzy hair.
閨蜜佇列裡的那個艾莉
And Ellie from the "Fun chum" column.
由於種種原因沒人理解的那個艾莉
Ellie, who, for reasons no one understands,
開著車四處載你的那個艾莉
drives you around in her car.
所以就請你快走去趕你的飛機吧
So, just go and please just catch your plane.
我們話還沒談完
We haven't finished the conversation.
沒話可談了
Well, um, we have.
談完了
We have.
除非
Unless...
在利物浦萊姆街火車站
in Liverpool Lime Street at...
在此時此刻  週五11點14分
11:14 on a Friday...
你選擇留下來
unless you choose to stay.
傑克
Jack.
傑克  你得上飛機了
Jack. You have to get on the plane.
你還在利物浦做啥呢
What are you still doing in Liverpool?
我今天沒法留下來
I can't stay today.
我明天要去錄深夜秀節目
I've gotta do The Late Late Show tomorrow,
我還要參加市場行銷會議
and I've gotta do the Marketing Meeting of Meetings
-太荒唐了  -這是你的機會
- and, oh, it's ridiculous... - And that was your chance.
別說了  快走吧
Now, quick, go.
請你走吧
Please, leave.
不好意思  你介意我拿一些薯片
Sorry. Hey, do you mind if I nick a couple of crisps
-路上吃嗎  -我希望你能幸福
- for the journey? - Look, I want you to be happy and,
並且能做出非同凡響的音樂  一直如此
and to make marvelous music. I always have.
-別  別全拿走  -好的
- No, not all the crisps! - Okay.
你就快走吧  走吧
Just go, go, go, go, go.
你的未來就在出門左轉
Your, your future is o-out the door and to the left.
那裡有個計程車站
A taxi rank.
對不起
I'm sorry.
對不起  對不起  對不起  對不
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm so...
洛杉磯
好了  歡迎來到
Okay. Welcome to the Major
重點市場行銷會議
Marketing Meeting of Meetings.
真是不敢相信今天我們這請來了傑克本尊
So amazing to have Jack himself right here in the building.
讓我們用熱烈的掌聲歡迎傑克
Give it up for Jack, y'all.
現在  傑克  我
Now, uh, Jack, I,
我相信在座的各位都和我有一樣的感受
I do believe I speak for everyone in attendance today
當我說
when I say...
-能和你一起製作 這張 -對
- it is the climax of our careers... - Yes!
令人心折的專輯  是我們事業的巔峰
...to be working on this mind-bending album with you.
掌聲在哪裡
Give it up, y'all.
你們沒必要每次都鼓掌
You, you don't have to clap every time.
但依然非常感謝
But thanks very much.
是謙遜先生啊
Mr. Modesty!
-為謙遜先生鼓掌  -不  我認真的
- Give it up for modesty! - No, seriously, d...
這就是他未經修飾的真實一面
That's what he does right off the top.
眾所周知  我們線上上發佈的歌曲
Now, as you all know, the songs we released online
已經引起了  史無前例的關注
have created unprecedented excitement.
對
Yes.
-對  -別這樣
- Yes. - No.
所以現在  把所有這些歌曲
So, now upon us falls
編進一張令人無法抗拒專輯裡
the mighty task of packaging everything together
這一艱巨任務落在了我們身上
into one single, irresistible album.
現在  傑克他自己有一些專輯名稱建議
Now, Jack came up with some title suggestions himself
我們研究了其中一些
and, uh, we worked on some of those.
要知道  我尤其被這個
You know, I especially got a kick out of
披頭士專輯名之一
佩伯軍士的孤獨之心俱樂部樂隊給逗樂了
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band.
對  這
Yeah, that's...
沒關係  笑吧  因為這確實很搞笑
It's okay to laugh, 'cause it's funny.
這個名字  太長了  傑克
It is. It's, uh, a lot of words, Jack.
但關鍵在於  我們就是覺得這個名字
But ultimately, in the end, we just felt it was, uh,
太不明所以了  對吧
uh, too confusing, right?
太令人費解了  另外
Too confusing. And, uh,
那個白色專輯的多樣性存在問題
The White Album has some diversity issues.
白色專輯：披頭士專輯名之一
怎麼會
How?
這就是一片白  傑克
That's a lot of white, Jack.
另外  我知道你對
And I know you were pretty enthusiastic
艾比路：披頭士專輯名之一
艾比路情有獨鍾  我想說
about Abbey Road. I gotta say,
它並沒什麼內涵
it didn't have a lot going for it...
我這樣跟你說吧
if I can put it to you like that.
這就是一條路  不過路上有一幫人
Uh, it's just a road, with a bunch of people
英美車道方向相反
在錯誤的車道上開車
driving down the wrong side of the street.
這不完全是我的真實意圖  不過
That's not exactly what I meant, but...
但我們現在探討出了一些自己的方案
But we've been developing some ideas of our own, now.
畢竟  我們不是吃閒飯的
You know, we weren't just sitting around.
我們只關注一件事  就是要讓這個男人
We focused on the one thing that makes this man here
在當今世界樂壇上獨樹一幟
unlike anyone else in the entire world of music today.
不搞什麼協作者  不搞聯名作曲
No collaborators, no cowriters,
不去採樣  抄襲其他樂曲
no samples, no steals, hmm?
不請卡迪·B助陣
No "featuring Cardi B,"
不請比伯合錄
no "featuring Bieber."
只有這位純粹的天才
Just the simple, pure genius...
傑克·馬利卡
絕代天驕
of One Man Only.
接下來  鑒於這位絕代天驕
And, as a second wave, because of the miracle
鬼斧神工  所以專輯的背面
that is One Man Only, it's just this.
就這樣
Just this.
所有歌曲
作詞作曲
一人完成
由Jack Malik
沒錯  我知道
Mmm, mmm. I know.
我知道
I know.
那麼  讓我們開始傑克行動吧
So, let Operation Jack begin!
每一周  線上發佈一首新歌
Each week, a new song online.
每一周  上一個新的電視節目
Each week, a new TV show.
我們先從科登開始  再到坎摩爾
We start with Corden, then we move to Kimmel,
Corden是《詹姆斯·科登深深夜秀》的主持人
Kimmel是《吉米雞毛秀》的主持人
再到法倫  再到科拜爾
then Fallon, then Colbert
Fallon是《吉米今夜秀》的主持人
Colbert是《史蒂芬·科拜爾晚間秀》的主持人
然後就是週四之夜現場演唱會
and then Thursday Night Live!
哇
Whoo!
歌  歌  歌  秀  秀  秀
Song, song, song. Show, show, show.
砰  砰  大賣特賣
Boom, bang, bazillions.
現在  我們就去賺大錢
Now, let's go make so much money that,
到明年耶誕節的這個時候  我們能
by this time next Christmas, we are wiping our asses
用純金的衛生紙擦屁股了
with solid-gold toilet paper.
女士們先生們  請歡迎
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome,
這位獨一無二的   傑克·馬利卡先生
the one, the only, Mr. Jack Malik!
傑克  我是你的粉絲  很高興見到你
Jack, I'm such a fan. It's great to meet you.
謝謝你來參加節目
Thank you for being here.
我聽過你的歌  它們真的
The songs of yours that I've heard, they are,
它們真的太棒了
they're amazing.
你當前的生活過得怎麼樣
What's life like for you at the moment right now?
我是說  歌迷對專輯的期待
I mean, the expectation for the album
正上升到了瘋狂的程度  不是嗎
is just rising to insane levels, isn't it?
是的  他們  他們真的很瘋狂
Yeah, well, they're... they're insane to me.
我說  這裡有誰非常期待這張專輯的
I mean, who here's excited about this album?
聽一下
Listen to that.
在這個年代  有時候16個人
In this age of, sometimes, 16 people
寫一首歌  突然之間來了一個小夥
writing on one song, suddenly, here's a guy,
就他和一把吉他  一個人就把歌寫出來了
him and a guitar, and he writes everything himself, on his own.
是啊  我的意思是  你知道的
Yeah. I mean... Well, you know, that's how it always
過去一直都這樣寫歌  像詹姆斯·泰勒
used to be, though, with, uh, with, like, James Taylor
或者史蒂夫·旺德  布魯斯·斯普林斯汀
or Stevie Wonder, Bruce Springsteen.
所以我不認為有什麼特別的
So I don't think it's that exceptional.
但真的只有你一個人嗎
But is it just you?
是的
Well, yes.
但是真的嗎
But is it?
嗯  是的
Well, y-yes. Yes, it is.
非常好
Excellent.
因為機緣巧合  請原諒我
Because as chance would have it, a-and do forgive me,
因為我們喜歡在節目中製造驚喜
because we-we love a surprise on this show.
該死的巧合
As chance would darn well have it,
我的後臺有兩個人
I've got two men backstage
他們聲稱這些歌是他們的
who claim that the songs are theirs.
事實上  他們說你所有的曲子
In fact, they say that all of your tunes
都是他們甲殼蟲樂隊的作品
are the work of their band, The Beatles.
我  我不知道
I d... I don't know...
我不
I don't...
好吧  讓我們來一看究竟  好嗎
Well, let's see how this plays out, shall we?
女士們先生們  不遠千里
Ladies and gentlemen, all the way
來自英國利物浦的  請歡迎
from Liverpool, England, please welcome,
保羅·麥卡特尼先生和林戈·斯塔爾先生
Mr. Paul McCartney and Mr. Ringo Starr!
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude. ♪
嘿
Hey.
在別克車上從後面幹我吧
Bang me backwards over a Buick.
這將是有史以來最棒的專輯
It's gonna be the greatest album of all time.
真的太棒了  夥計
It's really incredible, man.
-嘿  艾德  最近好嗎  -我只是來鎮上幾天
- Hey, Ed. How you doing? - Um, I'm just in town for a couple
我想我該來看看這位天才工作的樣子
of days. I thought I'd come and see the genius at work.
我只是想知道你寫歌的順序
I'm just trying to work out your process.
是先作曲還是先寫歌詞
Is it music first or lyrics first?
嗯  視情況而定
Um, it varies.
但是  就像這首歌  比如說
But, like, with this song, for instance, the, um,
《嘿，裘德》
the-the "Hey Jude" one
背後一定有什麼故事
must have some story behind it.
是的  有  有的
Well, yeah. It do... it does.
是關於我一個朋友的兒子的
So, it was the son of a friend of mine
他那時候很難過
who was having a hard time.
嗯  就  就這樣
Um, it, it, it just,
我寫出了一首安慰的歌
it came to me as a s... as a song of comfort.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
什麼
What?
我是說  我只是  我不能相信
I mean, I just... I don't believe you.
一首又一首曠世巨作  你知道嗎
It's one genius idea after the other, you know?
-對的  -不過  我確實有個建議
- Oh, right. - I do have a suggestion, though.
嗯  關於這首歌的
Um, about the song.
歌名是《嘿，裘德》
The-the title, "Hey Jude."
裘德好像有點過時
Jude is just, it's a bit old-fashioned.
-是那孩子的名字  對吧  -什麼孩子
- That was the kid's name, right? - What kid?
-歌中所唱的孩子  -哦  那孩子  孩子
- That the song's about. - Oh, the kid, the kid, the kid.
是的  那  那傷心的孩子
Yes, the-the... the sad kid.
現在  讓我給你個建議  好嗎
Now, l-let me just give you this advice, right?
歌名
Song title...
我也不會收你一分錢
I won't charge you a penny for it as well...
《嘿，裘弟》
"Hey Dude."
嗯
Um...
♪ 嘿  朱 ♪
♪ Hey, du... ♪
嘿  裘弟  你確定嗎
"Hey Dude," are you sure?
他說得對  那  那樣好多了
He's right. That's... that's so much better.
是嗎
Is he?
-真的嗎  -是的  是的
- Is it? - Yeah, yeah.
♪ 嘿  裘弟  別沮喪 ♪
♪ Hey, dude, don't make it bad ♪
是的  嗯
Yes. Mm-hmm.
-這不是真的  -絕對會成為
- This isn't real. - Definitely gonna be
這一代的最佳歌曲之一
one of the best songs of the generation.
♪ 嘿  裘弟 ♪
♪ Hey, dude ♪
醒醒  醒醒  傑克  醒醒
Wake up. Wake up, Jack. Wake up.
♪ 別沮喪 ♪
♪ Don't make it bad ♪
♪ 杜杜杜 ♪
♪ Du-du-du-du-du-du ♪
♪ 小弟  小弟  小弟 ♪
♪ Dudey-dudey-dudey ♪
♪ 嘿  裘弟 ♪
♪ Hey, dude ♪
絕對好多了
It's definitely better.
傑克  艾莉的電話
Jack, Ellie.
抱歉  夥計們  我要接一下電話
Oh, sorry, guys. I gotta take this.
給我一分鐘  艾德  抱歉
Just give me a minute, Ed. Sorry.
-艾爾  -傑克
- Elle. - Jack.
很高興你打電話來
I'm so glad you called.
我在這裡一點也不開心
I'm not enjoying myself here at all.
哦  好的  嗯
Oh, right. Well, um...
我有兩個小消息
I've got two bits of news.
我認真聽著
I'm riveted.
好的  嗯  第一個
All right. Well, the first one...
-大消息  -嗯
- big one. - Yeah?
碼頭酒店
The Pier Hotel.
什麼  在戈爾斯頓嗎  那個
What? In Gorleston? The place that
寧願倒閉也不讓我表演的酒店嗎
closed down rather than have me play?
對  那裡要重新開業了
Yes. It's reopening.
你絕對是開玩笑的
You're bloody kidding.
我絕對不是  這是絕對重新開業了
I am bloody not. It's re-bloody opening.
太棒了
That's amazing!
真是個大新聞
That's huge news!
那  那是個天大的消息
That's-that's-that's ma-bloody-ssive!
好吧  第二個是什麼
All right, what's the second?
雖然不能跟這個比  但也儘管告訴我
I mean, it can't be as big. But tell me anyway.
第二個是
n-number two is...
我在跟別人約會
I've been seeing someone.
好的
Right.
我認識他嗎
Do I know him?
是的  是加文
Yeah. It's Gavin.
我  我不想讓你從別人那裡知道
I-I didn't want you to find out from someone else.
每一天
Every day,
他都把我放到對的那一欄裡
he puts me in the right column.
當然
Of course.
真愛的位置
The "true love" one.
當然
Of course.
我得掛斷了
I've gotta go.
天啊  是的  你當然很忙
Ah, God. Yeah, course you do.
好的  再見  再見
Um, okay. Bye. Bye.
什麼  有什麼這麼緊急
What? What could possibly be so urgent
讓我打一個電話都不行
that I can't make a single phone call?!
我該死的怎麼能把這些歌唱好
How the hell am I supposed to get any of the songs right
要是你們一直圍著我轉
if you're just all clustering me
妨礙我創作
and stopping me from being creative?
如果我一直被跟著  我怎麼能有創作靈感
How can I ever be creative if I'm never ever left alone?!
好的
Okay.
那我們就不煩你了  天才
We'll leave you alone then, genius.
不  我不是  我很抱歉
No, I'm not... I'm sorry.
不  這  這是大明星的權利
No, it's g... It's, uh, it's superstar rights.
對待一起工作的人就像對待鞋上的屎一樣
Treat the people that you work with like shit on your shoes.
看來艾莉告訴你那個消息了
Ellie told you the news, then?
-是的  -你知道嗎  我從來都不明白
- Yeah. - You know, I never, never understood
你怎麼沒發現她身上的優點
what you didn't see in her.
我是說  如果我是你
I mean, I-if I'd been you,
一天兩次  我會像雄獅一樣迷戀她
twice a day I would have loved her up like a lusty lion.
洛基  容我讓你閉嘴
Rocky, if I ask you to just shut up,
真的  真的閉嘴  可以嗎
really, really, really shut up, would that be okay?
好的
Right.
我可以從新再說一遍嗎
Can I just start again and say,
這是個好消息  不是嗎
"Isn't it wonderful news?"
我希望他們在一起會很幸福
"And I hope they'll be very happy together"
生一堆漂漂亮亮的孩子  這樣說更好嗎
"and have gorgeous kids." Is that better?
不  更糟
No. It's worse.
我有第三個選擇  但是
I have got a third option. But...
我很抱歉  嗯  真的很抱歉  各位
I'm sorry. Um, I'm really sorry, everyone.
我只是
I'm just...
我壓力真的很大
I'm really stressed.
剛才什麼事這麼緊急
What was so urgent?
不  沒什麼
Oh, um, no, nothing.
只是我們今天得決定在什麼地方什麼時候
It's just we have to decide today where and when
推出這張專輯
we're going to launch the album.
所以  沒什麼大不了的  除了這可能是
So, nothing big, apart from probably
你愚蠢的人生中最大的一個決定
apart from probably the biggest decision of your stupid life.
-什麼  -你個混蛋
- What? - You ass.
我確實有一個想法
I do have one thought.
戈爾斯頓
像戈爾斯頓這樣的小鎮
And the little town of Gorleston
以前從沒遇到過這樣的盛況
has never seen anything like this before.
今天下午3點  在碼頭酒店l的屋頂上
At 3:00 p.M. today, on the rooftop of the Pier Hotel,
傑克·馬利卡  變身流行樂代表的本地男孩
Jack Malik, local boy turned pop phenomenon,
將發佈他的萬眾期待的第一張專輯
will premiere his highly anticipated first album.
消息似乎傳得很快
And word seems to have got out.
我們能
Can we, uh...?
看看這個
Wow. Look at this.
看看你
Look at you.
我不想打擾你
Didn't want to disturb.
只是想  你知道
Just wanted to, you know...
誰會想到呢
Well, it's... Who'd have thought?
當我們在樓下
While we were downstairs
喝著蘋果酒吃著果凍
drinking cider and eating jelly,
而你在樓上的房間裡寫著《她傾心於你》
you were up in your room writing "She Loves You."
對啊
Well...
你會唱我們的歌嗎
Are you, uh, you playing our song?
-你們的歌  -《順其自然》
- Your song? - "Let It Be."
我們從沒有忘記
Oh, well, we've never forgotten
我們是最先聽到這首歌的人
we were the first people to hear it.
至少是歌的開頭
Well, the start of it, at least.
三次
Three times.
我們為你感到驕傲
So proud.
我們漂亮的  光芒四射的孩子
Our beautiful, blazing boy.
別  我不想
Aw. Oh. Aw. Still, don't wanna...
小心你的衣服  親愛的
Mind your suit, love.
-它是藍色的 -是啊
- It's... blue. - Yeah.
-我們不打擾了  你忙吧  -好的
- We'll leave you to it. - Okay.
最後一件事  兒子
One last thing, son.
怎麼了  爸爸
Yeah, Dad?
這些三明治  我看到有金槍魚
The sandwiches. I see there's tuna.
你要把它們都吃光嗎
Are y-you gonna finish them all?
-或者如果你不  -不  請全拿走吧
- Or if you don't...? - No, please take them all.
啊  這一天 真是太美好了
Oh, what a day. What an amazing day.
打擾了
Sorry.
傑克  傑克  傑克
Jack! Jack! Jack!
傑克  傑克
Jack! Jack!
你看起來不錯
Well, you look good.
瞧這緊身褲
That's a tight pant.
很好  瞧咱們這下頜角和下巴頦
Okay. We've got a jaw and a chin.
真不錯
Ooh! That's not bad.
一定行的  會成功的
That's... This'll work. This'll work. Mmm.
不要
Don't...
-怎麼了  -沒事兒
- What? - Nothing.
誰啊
Yeah?
-嗨  艾莉  -嗨
- Oh. Hi, Ellie. - Hi.
進來吧
Come in.
-這是誰啊  -黛布拉  這是艾莉
- And who have we here? - Um, Debra, this is Ellie.
艾莉  這是黛布拉  我的經紀人
Ellie, this is Debra, my agent.
不會吧
No!
你就是那個艾莉
The Ellie?
他有提起過我嗎
Oh! He's mentioned me?
沒  沒  逗你玩呢  我對他的生活
No, no. I'm kidding. I know nothing
一無所知  因為對我來說他就是個產品
about his life because he's a product to me.
除非你是他以前的經紀人
Unless you're the one that was his manager.
在這種情況下
In which case, wow.
放棄了他可是個巨大的錯誤
Huge mistake giving that up.
越扯越偏了  不是嗎  快回到碼頭酒店來
Oh, it's surreal, isn't it? Being back at the Pier Hotel.
確實有點兒
Yeah, indeed.
-我得去看看舞臺了-對
- I'm gonna go look at the stage, yeah?  - Mm.
-這邊請  -好
- It's this way. - Yeah.
十點開新聞發佈會
Press conference in ten.
再見  織女牛郎
Goodbye, lovebirds.
對不起  我不該離開萊姆街
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have left Lime Street, okay?
-這是個嚴重的錯誤  -不
- It was a terrible mistake. - Oh, no.
-請別這麼說  -我們能不能
- Don't say that, please. - Can we...?
-別這麼說  -艾莉
- Don't say that. - Ellie...
我聽了你的新歌
I-I've heard your new songs.
-簡直太不可思議了  -不  不是這樣的
- They're incredible. - O-Okay. No, they aren't.
我甚至都不知道你是誰了
I don't even know who you are anymore.
在那次車禍之後  一切都變了
Everything changed after the accident.
-到底發生了什麼  -傑克
- Wha-What happened? - Jack.
-這是加文  -傑克  傑克
- And here's Gavin.  - Jack, Jack.
傑克
Jack!
-傑克  傑克  傑克  -嗨  哥們
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack. Oh, hey, mate.
-傑克  -你最近咋樣
- Jack. - How you doing, man?
傑克  傑克
Jack. Jack.
-我不知道該說啥好  -是嗎
- I don't know what to say. - Oh, really?
你剛不是一直在喊  傑克
It sounds like you do and it's, "Jack."
傑克
Jack!
我們只是來祝你好運
We were just coming to say good luck and, um,
大獲成功
break a leg.
break a leg 字面意義為  摔斷一條腿
如果我從天臺上掉下來  摔斷一條腿
Yeah. Well, if I fall off the roof, then a broken leg
這結局也挺不錯
will be a good result.
好啦  我們走
All right, then. Let's go.
快走吧
Come on.
艾莉
Ellie.
看起來好安靜啊
Looks pretty quiet.
那我們就少唱幾首吧
Well, maybe we should do a slightly shorter set?
我是說真的很安靜
I mean really quiet.
你倆來幹嘛的啊
What do you want?
我倆來演出的  我是樂手
Uh, we're here for the gig. I'm the musician.
這有點兒難辦
Well, that's pretty tricky.
我們三個禮拜前就關門了
'Cause we closed three weeks ago.
不用我多說了吧
I'd take it as a hint, I would.
我想我必須得放棄兼職
I'm gonna have to give up the part-time jobs,
回去教書了
go back to teaching.
咋的了
What?
不行  別回去教書
No. Don't go back to teaching.
我別無選擇了
I've got no choice.
傑克  回去教書
Jack, if you go back to teaching,
才會讓你別無選擇
that is when you've got no choice.
因為那樣你會把你所有的天賦
Yeah, because you'll end up putting all your genius
都放在那些孩子身上
into all those kids and then you won't
你就沒有任何想像力和精力搞音樂了
have any i-imagination or energy left to put into your music,
音樂對你才是最重要的
which really matters.
求你了
Please...
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
你這個瘋狂到有點兒癲狂的女人
Crazy, slightly mad woman.
從來沒有人能在
No one has ever written
這麼短的時間內寫出這些偉大的歌曲
this many great songs in this short a time.
你是怎麼做到的
How do you do it?
老實說我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
有時候好像別人已經
Sometimes it feels like someone else
把所有的歌曲都寫好了
has written all the songs.
是誰啊
Any idea who?
《永遠的草莓地》這首歌背後的靈感是什麼
What's the inspiration behind "Strawberry Fields Forever"?
《永遠的草莓地》：約翰·列儂創作的單曲  收錄於1967年6月發行的專輯《佩珀軍士的寂寞芳心俱樂部》中
-這個嘛  -你最喜歡誰
- Well... - Who was your favorite,
約翰  保羅  喬治還是林戈
John, Paul, George or Ringo?
約翰  保羅  喬治  林戈：披頭士樂隊四位成員
-你說啥  -誰對你影響最大
- Sorry? - Who's your greatest influence?
《那條漫長而曲折的路》：保羅·麥卡特尼創作的單曲  收錄在1970年3月發行的專輯《順其自然》中
傑克你真在  寫了《那條漫長而曲折的路》嗎
Jack, is it true that you wrote "The Long and Winding Road" in...
你為什麼不像他們一樣在艾比路錄音呢
W-Why don't you record in Abbey Road like they did?
艾比路：艾比路錄音棚曾是披頭士樂隊錄製專輯的所在地
啥時候能看到另一張專輯  傑克
When can we see another album, Jack?
傑克  《順其自然》這首歌背後有啥故事
Jack, what's the story behind "Let it Be"?
《順其自然》：保羅·麥卡特尼創作的單曲  收錄在1970年3月發行的同名專輯中
你是怎麼寫出《昨日》這首歌的
How'd you come up with "Yesterday"?
《昨日》：保羅·麥卡特尼創作的單曲  收錄於1965年8月發行的專輯《救命》中
非常感謝大家  我們現在得上天臺了
Thank you so much. We have to go to the roof now.
我們待會兒見
We'll see you later.
傑克  你寫的第一首歌是啥
Jack, what was the first song you ever wrote?
傑克  你今天會給我們帶來什麼演出
Jack, what are you gonna play for us today?
其實他們的酒吧還挺贊的
It's a nice bar they've got down there, actually.
你沒喝酒吧
You haven't been drinking, have you?
沒  我沒喝  好吧  我喝了
No, I have not. Well, y-yeah, I have.
我發現中午喝幾杯能讓我機靈點兒
But I find a couple of pints midday sharpens my senses.
我不確定這能行  老兄
I'm not sure it does, mate.
行了  開始吧
Right, here goes.
其實  在開門之前  我想說
Actually, before I open this door, can I just say,
很長一段時間我一直都不明白我為啥出生
for a long time I didn't really know why I'd been born.
覺著沒啥意義
Felt a bit pointless.
但現在我明白了
But now I do know.
我生來就是為了服務有史以來最偉大的音樂家
I was born to serve the greatest musician of all time.
全世界都在翹首以待
It is my honor now to open this door
等我現在打開這扇門  我覺得無比榮耀
for the moment the entire world has been waiting for.
謝謝你  洛基
Thanks, Rock.
這當然也是一次地獄般的旅行  不是嗎
Oh, it's certainly been one hell of a journey, hasn't it?
沒錯  確實
So it has. So it has.
好了
Right.
開始咯
Here goes.
不對不對  開錯門了
No, that's not... Uh, wrong door.
讓我們接著一起旅行
Um, let us, let us continue our journey together.
好了
Right.
現在真的開始咯
Here it does go.
傑克
Jack!
傑克  傑克  傑克  傑克  傑克
Jack! Jack! Jack! Jack! Jack! Jack!
唱《夏日之歌》
謝謝戈爾斯頓
Thank you, Gorleston!
傑克  傑克  傑克
Jack! Jack! Jack!
加油啊  傑克
Come on, Jack!
♪ 當我年輕的時候 ♪
♪ When I was younger ♪
此曲為披頭士樂隊的歌曲《救命》  由約翰·列儂和保羅·麥卡特尼共同創作  收錄于1965年發行的同名專輯中
♪ 比現在還要年輕很多的時候 ♪
♪ So much younger than today ♪
♪ 我從不需要任何人任何形式的幫忙 ♪
♪ I never needed anybody's help in any way ♪
♪ 但現在青春飛逝  我不再那麼自信 ♪
♪ But now these days are gone, I'm not so self-assured ♪
♪ 我發現自己改變了觀念  敞開了心扉 ♪
♪ I found that I've changed my mind, I opened up the door ♪
♪ 如果可以請你幫我吧  我有點沮喪 ♪
♪ Help me if you can, I'm feeling down ♪
♪ 我真的很感激你在我身旁 ♪
♪ And I do appreciate you being 'round ♪
♪ 幫我一把讓我重新振作起來吧 ♪
♪ Help me get my feet back on the ground ♪
♪ 求求你  請你幫我一下 ♪
♪ Won't you please, please help me? ♪
♪ 現在我的生活  在很多方面 ♪
♪ And now my life has changed ♪
♪ 都改變了很多 ♪
♪ in oh,so many ways ♪
♪ 我的獨立似乎在陰霾中消失不見 ♪
♪ My independence seems to vanish in the haze ♪
♪ 但我時常感到特別不安 ♪
♪ But every now and then I feel so insecure ♪
♪ 我發現我從沒如此需要你的陪伴 ♪
♪ I find that I need you like I've never done before ♪
♪ 如果可以請你幫我吧  我有點沮喪 ♪
♪ Help me if you can, I'm feeling down ♪
♪ 我真的很感激你在我身旁 ♪
♪ And I do appreciate you being 'round ♪
♪ 幫我一把讓我重新振作起來吧 ♪
♪ Help me get my feet back on the ground ♪
♪ 求求你  請你幫幫我  救救我 ♪
♪ Won't you please, please help me, help me, help me ♪
♪ 救救我吧 ♪
♪ Help me! ♪
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
再堅持下  行嗎
Just hang on a minute, all right?
這倆人等了一個小時想見你
these... these two have been waiting to see you
他們倆真的好古怪
for an hour and they're genuinely a weird pair.
要不要我叫他們直接離開  還是
Shall I tell them to sod right off? Or...
不
No.
不  讓他們進來
No, let 'em in.
進來吧  怪咖們  給你們兩分鐘
All right, weirdos. Two minutes.
你可以走了  洛基  我沒事
You can go now, Rock. I'll be fine.
我想我們可不可以聊聊
I wonder if we could have a little talk.
行
Yeah.
我看見你去了便士小巷和草莓地
'Cause I saw you went to Penny Lane and Strawberry Fields.
《便士小巷》：保羅·麥卡特尼創作的單曲  於1967年2月發行
沒錯
Yeah.
還有埃莉諾·瑞格的墳墓
Eleanor Rigby's grave.
《愛琳·盧比》：約翰·列儂與保羅·麥卡特尼共同創作的單曲  收錄於1966年8月發行的專輯《左輪手槍》中
我知道
I know.
你沒法唱出
'Cause you can't sing songs about places
你從沒去過的地方
you've never even been to.
-對  -是的
- No. - No.
我也是這麼想的
I thought as much.
我們到這兒就是想說聲謝謝來著
Well, we just wanted to say thank you, that's all.
謝我啥
Thank me?
我們三個人大概是世上唯一能記得這些歌曲的了
We three seem to be the only ones who remember.
而且我們倆也不會唱
And we can't sing.
所以  我們只是想說  非常感謝
So, we just wanted to say... thanks very much.
我也是  發自肺腑的
Myself also. From bottom of heart.
我的天
Oh, my God!
我以為你們要逮捕我  或者
I thought you were gonna arrest me, or...
-不是  只是聽了這些歌曲很高興  -太好了
- No. It's just lovely to hear the songs. - Yeah.
我好想念它們
I have missed them so.
就是歌詞一句都想不起來了
Can't remember any of the lyrics.
-對  我也正在努力想呢  -我明白
- No. I'm struggling there as well.  - I know.
《為了凱特先生的利益》這首歌詞順序全錯了
"For the Benefit of Mr. Kite!" is in completely the wrong order.
《為了凱特先生的利益》：約翰·列儂創作的單曲   收錄於1967年6月發行的專輯《佩珀軍士的寂寞芳心俱樂部》中
-真是一團糟  -是啊
- Very big mess, indeed. - Oh, yeah.
怎麼還有《嘿，裘弟》  真假的
And "Hey Dude"? Really?
我沒法道歉  全怪該死的艾德·希蘭
I can't apologize. It was bloody Ed Sheeran.
不過這太令人震驚了
But this is amazing!
我的天啊
Oh, God!
我感覺自己像是在外國東奔西跑
'Cause I feel like I-I've been running around
最後終於碰見了兩個
a foreign country and I've finally bumped into two people
會講英語的人
who can speak English.
因為沒人聽過
'Cause no one has ever heard of
《佩珀軍士的寂寞芳心俱樂部》
Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band.
《佩珀軍士的寂寞芳心俱樂部》：披頭士樂隊的第8張錄音室專輯  於1967年6月發行
也沒人住在黃色潛水艇裡
No one's ever lived in a yellow submarine
此曲為披頭士樂隊的歌曲《黃色潛水艇》  由保羅·麥卡特尼創作  收錄於1966年8月發行的專輯《左輪手槍》中
♪ 黃色潛水艇  黃色潛水艇 ♪
♪ A yellow submarine.A yellow submarine ♪
♪ 黃色潛水艇 ♪
♪ A yellow submarine ♪
-我們都住在黃色潛水艇裡  -是啊
- We all live in a yellow submarine. - We do.
我住在章魚花園
I-I live in "Octopus's Garden."
《章魚樂園》：林戈·斯塔爾創作的單曲  收錄於1969年9月發行的專輯《艾比路》中
是啊
Yes!
你聽著
Oh, you see.
這是我的設想  小傑克
See, here's my take, young Jack.
一個沒有甲殼蟲樂隊的世界
A world without The Beatles,
是一個極其差勁的世界
is a world that's infinitely worse.
所以  謝謝你
So, thank you.
好好把握它
And use it well.
我在努力  但是好難
I'm trying, but it's hard.
那麼多鈔票和成功向我湧來
There's so much money and success coming,
但我覺得自己純粹就是靠騙人過活
but I feel like I've become the definition of living a lie.
我看得出來這事可能確實很艱難
Well, I can see it might feel like that.
我們覺得這可能能幫到你
We thought this might help.
怎麼說
I beg your pardon?
這張紙裡記錄了我們
Here. We've done...
做過的許多調查
a lot of digging.
你好
Hello.
有什麼事嗎
Can I help?
我不確定
I don't know.
你是約翰嗎
Are you John?
是的
That's right.
-你是利物浦人嗎  -是的
- From Liverpool? - That's right.
很榮幸見到你
It's an honor to meet you.
約翰
John?
什麼事
Yeah?
你這輩子過得幸福嗎
Have you had a happy life?
非常幸福
Very.
但並不成功吧
But not successful.
我只說了非常幸福
I just said "very happy."
這已經算是成功了
That means successful.
日復一日地做著我喜歡的工作
Did a job I enjoyed day after day.
駕船環遊世界
Sailed the world.
為我信仰的事物付出努力並且還
Fought for things I believed in and won...
成功了好幾次
a couple of times.
找到了一個心愛的姑娘
Found a woman I loved.
為了留住她也付出了許多努力
Fought hard to keep her, too.
和她一起過了一輩子
Lived my life with her.
為了留住她付出努力是嗎
Fought hard for her?
這件事過程很
There were complica...
抱歉  你叫什麼名字來著
Sorry, what-what's your name?
傑克
Jack.
這件事過程很複雜  傑克
There were complications, young Jack.
得與失
Loss and gain.
傲慢與偏見
Prejudice and pride.
但是
But...
現在看來  這一切都
it all turned out just...
美妙絕倫
fab.
你的感情生活怎麼樣
How's your love life?
很爛
Bad.
我沒能留住她
I let her slip away.
努力把她追回來
Try to get her back.
你想知道幸福的秘訣嗎
You want a good life?
這並不複雜
It's not complicated.
只需要告訴你愛的姑娘你愛她
Tell the girl you love that you love her.
並且在合適的時候向大家說出真相
And tell the truth to everyone whenever you can.
我能抱一下你嗎
Can I give you a hug?
啥
What?
能見到你真是太好了
It's so good to see you.
你多少歲了
How old are you?
78歲
Seventy-eight.
太棒了
Fantastic!
你活到78歲了
You made it to 78.
你真是個怪人
You're a very strange man.
但是抱一個吧
But go ahead.
你真的很需要去看看精神問題
You need serious psychiatric help.
現在不用了
Not anymore.
♪ 我迷上了你曼妙的身姿 ♪
♪ I'm in love with the shape of you ♪
傑克
Jack.
-艾德  -有什麼事嗎
- Ed. - How can I help?
我有一個不情之請
I need to ask quite a big and strange favor.
{\fn\fs42\b1\i1\bord3\3c&H5514dc&\4c&H5514dc&\1a&Hff&\3a&H33&\4a&Hff&\move(700,250,-200,250,1280,4720)}溫布利
來啦老弟
My boy.
黛布拉
Debra.
艾德真倒楣啊
Poor Ed.
那個施洗者約翰
John the Baptist.
一個大好人
Nice guy,
寫過一兩首不錯的歌  但主要還是由於
one or two pretty good songs, but was basically
給你內心帶去了溫暖
warming the world up for you.
像是救世主一樣
The Messiah.
於是就快要成為歷史上最偉大的音樂家了
Soon to be the most successful artist in the history of music.
也正是因為他  我要
And the reason I'm going to be buying
在馬里布買下  不是一棟房子
not just one more house in Malibu,
而是整個海灘
but the entire beachfront.
很高興見到你  黛布拉
Well, it's good to see you, Debra. Um...
所以  有人知道你為什麼會來這裡嗎
d... So, does anybody know why you're actually here?
我要唱幾首歌來給艾德的演出錦上添花
I'm gonna spice up Ed's set with a couple of songs,
然後
and then, um,
我想宣佈一些事情
there's a little something I want to say.
唱歌啊  我喜歡聽歌
Songs, I love songs.
至於你想宣佈的事
Thing you'd like to say...
我建議你控制好時間
I'd keep it brief.
我以前聽你講話總是味同嚼蠟
I've never heard you say anything interesting before.
我很好奇今晚你為何會有如此突破
I don't know why tonight would be the big breakthrough.
祝你演出順利
Have a good show.
謝謝你  很有幫助
Thank you. Helpful.
輪到你上場了
You're on.
好的
Okay.
-她在這裡嗎  -在
- Is she here? - Yeah.
好的
Okay.
-記好我們的計畫  -記好了
- Remember the plan. - Yeah.
等我唱到最後一首歌的時候
When I get to the last song...
別說了  我記得
Hey, I'm ready.
謝謝大家
Thank you.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
現在  演出還沒有完全結束
Now, the gig is not quite over.
我還要給大家帶來最後的驚喜
I have one last surprise for you all.
我要請出一位老朋友
I'm gonna bring on an old friend.
我因為他是我俄羅斯之旅的助演而認識他
I know him as my dodgy Moscow support act,
你們因為他寫了非常美妙的歌曲而認識他
you know him as a man that writes very, very good songs.
溫布利體育場的各位
Wembley Stadium,
掌聲歡迎傑克·馬利卡先生
please make some noise for Mr. Jack Malik!
好了  交給你了  大師
All right. Over to you, maestro.
謝謝
Thanks.
溫布利的各位
Wembley,
掌聲歡迎
please welcome to the stage,
史上最偉大的人類
the greatest human being who ever lived.
我最好的朋友
My best friend.
你們的偶像
Your hero.
傑克·馬利卡先生上臺
Sir Jack Malik!
傑克
Yeah, Jack! Whoo!
傑克  傑克
Jack! Jack! Jack! Whoo!
♪ 她那時只有  十七歲 ♪
♪ Well, she was just 17 ♪
♪ 我的意思  你能領會 ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ 她如此貌美 ♪
♪ And the way she looked ♪
傑克
Jack!
♪ 無人能媲美 ♪
♪ Was way beyond compare ♪
♪ 太陽出來了 ♪
♪ Here comes the sun Doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ 太陽出來了  而我想說 ♪
♪ Here comes the sun, and I say ♪
♪ 一切好起來了 ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
所以你什麼時候開始發現
So, when did you first realize
你兒子優秀得不像是你親生的
that your son was too good for you?
♪ 太陽  太陽  出來了 ♪
♪ Sun, sun, sun, here it comes ♪
♪ 我回到了  我回到了 ♪
♪ Back in the US, back in the US ♪
♪ 我回到了蘇聯 ♪
♪ Back in the USSR ♪
♪ 你什麼都說不出來 ♪
♪ Nothing you can say ♪
♪ 但是你可以服從遊戲規則的安排 ♪
♪ But you can learn how to play the game ♪
♪ 這很簡單 ♪
♪ It's easy ♪
♪ 做不了的東西你做不出來 ♪
♪ Nothing you can make that can't be made ♪
♪ 救不了的人 ♪
♪ Nothing you can save ♪
管樂隊都請來了啊
Brass band, huh?
♪ 你救不來 ♪
♪ That can't be saved ♪
這些小丑要我們出錢嗎
Are we paying these jokers?
♪ 你什麼都做不來 ♪
♪ Nothing you can do ♪
♪ 但你可以早點找回自我的存在 ♪
♪ But you can learn how to be you in time ♪
♪ 這很簡單 ♪
♪ It's easy ♪
所有人
Everybody!
♪ 你只需要愛 ♪
♪ All you need is love ♪
到後臺來  艾莉  怎麼了
Come backstage, Ellie. What?
借過一下
Coming through.
♪ 你只需要愛 ♪
♪ All you need is love ♪
好的  借過一下
Yeah, excuse me.
♪ 愛  你只需要愛 ♪
♪ Love, love is all you need ♪
♪ 你只需要愛 ♪
♪ All you need is love ♪
現在所有人一起唱
All together now!
來吧  快點  過來  看到那個了嗎
Come, come, come, come, come, come, come. See that?
所有人一起
Everybody!
對  你就
Yeah. Just...
就站在那裡  對  站在那裡
Just stand right there. Yeah, stand there.
-相信我  -什麼
- Trust me. - What?
♪ 你只需要愛 ♪
♪ Love is all you need. ♪
現在  有個
And now, there's, um,
有個人我想給你們介紹一下
there's someone I'd like to introduce you to.
不知道畫面能不能轉到後臺的攝像機
If we could just switch on the backstage camera.
是艾莉
Oh! Oh! It's Ellie!
這個人就是艾莉
This is Ellie.
Ellie
Hi, Ellie!
在我還無人問津時
And when I had no fans,
艾莉是我唯一的粉絲
Ellie was my only fan.
世界上唯一支持我的人
The only person in the world who believed in me.
所以  我問艾德  今晚
And that's why, tonight, I asked Ed
我能不能上臺演出
if I could come on and play,
因為我想告訴她  和你們
'cause I want to tell her... and you,
-我都做了些什麼  -你在說什麼呢
- what I've done. - What are you saying?
抱歉  艾莉  我一直都沒說實話
Darn it, Ellie, I've been untrue.
我今晚唱的歌實際上都是
All the songs I've sung tonight were really written
由四個男人寫的  他們是約翰·列儂
and performed by four men called John Lennon,
保羅·麥卡特尼  喬治·哈里森和林戈·斯塔.
Paul McCartney, George Harrison and Ringo Starr.
也就是甲殼蟲樂隊
The Beatles.
他們是真正的天才
They were the real geniuses.
我  我只能算是一個
Me, I'm just a, sort of,
把這些天籟之音
go-between to, well,
帶到這個世界上的中間人
get their astonishing stuff into the world.
-甲殼蟲樂隊  -而且  我
- Beatles? - And, uh, I-I
我把他們的傑作冒充成我自己的了
I passed their amazing work off as my own
所以我才能看起來也這麼厲害
so I could look like I was amazing, too.
我希望你們都知道的是  我不準備收錢
I want you all to know that I'm not gonna take any money
因為這些並不是我的作品
for this work that isn't mine.
所以  你們可以免費獲取所有的歌曲
So, you can have all the songs for free.
洛基  開始吧
Rocky, do it.
好的  開始吧
Right. Here goes.
它們現在正在網上免費發佈
They're being released, for free, online now.
另外我希望你們別再為這些歌追捧我了
And I'd love to not take any more praise for it.
所以
So, um...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我站在這裡  還有一件事要說
And while I'm at it, there's one other thing to say as well,
因為  我已經做了兩次蠢事了
because... I've been a fool twice over.
我要感謝艾莉
And I want to thank Ellie...
對我的愛
for her love.
艾莉
And, Ellie...
艾爾
Elle...
我愛你
I love you.
我一直都愛著你
I always have.
向來如此
Always.
今晚講的話夠多了
That's definitely enough talking for one night.
但確實是一場狂歡
But it's been a blast.
我們愛你  傑克
We love you, Jack!
我們依然愛你
We still love you!
舞臺怎麼走
Where's the stage?
這是幾樓
What floor is this?
他媽的舞臺怎麼走
Where is the goddamn stage?!
-天哪  -我知道
- Oh, my God. - I know.
要接受的信息量有點大
That's a lot of information to take in.
我明白
I know.
如果你提前告訴我要上大銀幕
Well, if you'd told me I was gonna be on the big screen,
我就能把頭髮做一下的
I'd have got my hair done.
對不起了
I'm sorry.
沒有一首歌是你寫的嗎
You didn't write any of the songs?
沒有
No.
這種行為很不好
That is very bad behavior.
在全球範圍來說
On a global scale.
是的  非常不好
Yeah. It's very bad.
好吧  這話有點奇怪
Well, this is a strange one.
當然  我知道我總是第二名
Of course I've always known I was number two.
但第二名也不錯
But that's not a bad place to be.
很多最好的歌都不是第一名
Some of the best songs never made it to number one.
比如說 果醬樂隊的《普通人》
"Common People" by Pulp, for a start.
肯定是經典
It's a total classic.
顯然  我只是希望艾莉能快樂
And obviously all I want is for Ellie to be happy.
加文
Gavin.
你是我見過最好的人
Best man I ever met.
-謝謝你  加文  -他在這裡
- Thank you, Gavin. - He's here.
-他在這裡  -快走
- He's here! - Go on.
-怎麼了  -天啊
- What is that? - Oh, god.
-快走  -傑克
- Go! - Jack!
-傑克  -天啊  我們得趕緊走
- Jack! - Oh, my... We should definitely go!
-對  對  -該死
- Yeah, yeah. - Shit!
那個撒謊的死賤人在哪裡
Where's that lying son of a bitch?
讓開  蠢貨們
Move, idiots!
快看  他在這裡
Look, he's here!
傑克
Jack!
傑克  請帶我一起走
Jack, please take me with you.
沒人會雇我
No one else will employ me.
我  我工作幹得一團糟
I-I'm rubbish at my job.
洛基  幫我攔住他們
Just hold them off, Rocky.
看在錢的份上  站住
In the name of money, stop!
回來  你這個愚蠢的英國佬
Get back here, you stupid, English mother...
-對不起  黛布拉  -傑克
- Uh, ooh. Sorry, Debra. - Jack!
黛布拉  別這樣  太丟人了
Debra, stop this. You're embarrassing yourself.
傑克
Jack!
♪ 趁此良辰 ♪
♪ It's such a beautiful night ♪
♪ 訂立誓言 ♪
♪ To make a change in our lives ♪
♪ 夜色溫柔  美酒相伴 ♪
♪ East Anglian sky, empty bottle of wine ♪
♪ 身側有你 ♪
♪ I got you by my side ♪
♪ 海誓山盟 ♪
♪ Talking 'bout love and life ♪
♪ 深情相望  幸甚之至 ♪
♪ Oh, how lucky you're mine when I look in your eyes ♪
♪ 良辰美景  兩情相悅 ♪
♪ What a wonderful way to spend a moment or two ♪
♪ 喁喁細語  情話綿綿 ♪
♪ To be lying awake and be here talking to you ♪
♪ 深情告白  命中註定 ♪
♪ I got somethin' to say and know what I gotta do ♪
♪ 天地可鑒  日月可表 ♪
♪ To be making a change, now the moment of truth ♪
♪ 在天願做比翼鳥 ♪
♪ Why am I feeling so nervous? ♪
♪ 在地願為連理枝 ♪
♪ When things are going so perfect ♪
♪ 天長地久有時盡 ♪
♪ But I know that it's worth it ♪
♪ 此愛綿綿無絕期 ♪
♪ To spend forever with you ♪
♪ 鼓起勇氣 ♪
♪ And so I count to three ♪
♪ 躬身行禮 ♪
♪ And get on one knee ♪
♪ 叩問卿意 ♪
♪ And I ask you ♪
♪ 執子之手 ♪
♪ Darling, honestly ♪
♪ 與子偕老 ♪
♪ I've waited all this time ♪
♪ 死生契闊 ♪
♪ Just to make it right ♪
♪ 與子相悅 ♪
♪ So, I'll ask you tonight ♪
♪ 之子於歸 ♪
♪ "Will you marry me?" ♪
♪ 宜其家室 ♪
♪ Just say yes ♪
♪ 一生  一世  一雙人 ♪
♪ One word, one love, one life... ♪
我覺得就像哈利·波特打敗伏地魔以後
Oh, I feel like Harry Potter after he defeated Voldemort.
最終  所以事都回到正軌
At last, everything can go back to normal.
正常很好  對嗎
Isn't normal wonderful?
誰
Who?
你問什麼
Sorry?
哈利·波特  是誰
Harry Potter. Who's he?
♪ 美滿良緣 ♪
♪ Your hand in mine ♪
♪ 天作之合 ♪
♪ Some things were just meant to be ♪
哈利·波特
♪ 心心相印 ♪
♪ Hearts intertwined ♪
哈樂德·波特
♪ 天作之合 ♪
♪ Some things were just meant to be ♪
不是誰
No one.
♪ 花好月圓 ♪
♪ In perfect time ♪
沒什麼
Nothing.
♪ 天作之合 ♪
♪ Some things were just meant to be ♪
該睡覺了
Time for bed.
♪ 伉儷情深 ♪
♪ Oh, you and I ♪
時間
Time.
♪ 天作之合 ♪
♪ Some things were just meant to be. ♪
現今
♪ 德斯蒙德在市場裡有輛手推車 ♪
♪ Desmond has a barrow in the marketplace ♪
♪ 茉莉是樂隊裡的一名歌手 ♪
♪ Molly is a singer with a band ♪
♪ 德斯蒙德說他喜歡茉莉的長相 ♪
♪ Desmond says to Molly, "Girl, I like your face" ♪
♪ 茉莉握著他的手說 ♪
♪ And Molly says this as she takes him by the hand ♪
♪ 奧布-拉-迪  奧布-拉-達 ♪
♪ Ob-la-di, ob-la-da ♪
♪ 生活在繼續  老兄 ♪
♪ Life goes on, brah ♪
♪ 啦啦  他們的生活如何繼續 ♪
♪ Lala, how their life goes on ♪
好
Okay.
♪ 幾年裡他們建立了美滿家庭 ♪
♪ In a couple of years they have built a home sweet home ♪
♪ 有幾個孩子在院子裡奔跑 ♪
♪ With a couple of kids running in the yard ♪
♪ 是德斯蒙德和茉莉·鐘斯的孩子 ♪
♪ Of Desmond and Molly Jones ♪
♪ 哈-哈-哈-哈 ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ 市場裡從此歡聲笑語 ♪
♪ Happy ever after in the marketplace ♪
♪ 茉莉讓孩子們來幫忙 ♪
♪ Molly lets the children lend a hand ♪
原歌詞是德斯蒙德讓孩子們來幫忙
♪ 德斯蒙德在家做美容 ♪
♪ Desmond stays at home and does a pretty face ♪
原歌詞是茉莉在家做美容
♪ 晚上她是樂隊的歌手 ♪
♪ And in the evening she's a singer in a band ♪
最後一遍
One last time!
♪ 奧布-拉-迪  奧布-拉-達 ♪
♪ Ob-la-di, ob-la-da ♪
♪ 生活在繼續  老兄 ♪
♪ Life goes on, brah ♪
♪ 啦啦  他們的生活如何繼續 ♪
♪ Lala, how their life goes on ♪
♪ 奧布-拉-迪  奧布-拉-達 ♪
♪ Ob-la-di, ob-la-da ♪
♪ 生活在繼續  老兄 ♪
♪ Life goes on, brah ♪
♪ 啦啦  他們的生活如何繼續 ♪
♪ Lala, how their life goes on ♪
如果你想開心
And if you want some fun!
♪ 就說奧布-拉-迪-布拉-達 ♪
♪ Take Ob-la-di-bla-da. ♪
很好
Yes!
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
昨日奇跡
♪ 別沮喪 ♪
♪ Don't make it bad ♪
♪ 唱首悲傷的歌  舒緩一下自己 ♪
♪ Take a sad song and make it better ♪
♪ 記得將歌唱入你心田 ♪
♪ Remember to let her into your heart ♪
♪ 世界就能 ♪
♪ Then you can start ♪
♪ 開始好轉 ♪
♪ To make it better ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  別害怕 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude, don't be afraid ♪
♪ 你天生就要 ♪
♪ You were made to ♪
♪ 勇於克服恐懼 ♪
♪ Go out and get her ♪
♪ 當你理解的那一刻 ♪
♪ The minute you let her under your skin ♪
♪ 世界就開始好轉 ♪
♪ Then you begin to make it better ♪
♪ 當你感受痛苦的滋味 ♪
♪ And anytime you feel the pain ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  要忍耐 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude, refrain ♪
♪ 別把世界的重擔 ♪
♪ Don't carry the world ♪
♪ 都往肩上扛 ♪
♪ Upon your shoulders ♪
♪ 要知道  傻瓜才會 ♪
♪ For well you know that it's a fool ♪
♪ 假裝堅強 ♪
♪ Who plays it cool ♪
♪ 才會把自己的世界 ♪
♪ By making his world ♪
♪ 變得冷漠 ♪
♪ A little colder ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 別讓我失望 ♪
♪ Don't let me down ♪
♪ 找到真愛就要勇敢追求 ♪
♪ You have found her, now go and get her ♪
♪ 記得讓她走進你心田 ♪
♪ Remember to let her into your heart ♪
♪ 世界就能開始好轉 ♪
♪ Then you can start to make it better ♪
♪ 要拿得起放得下 ♪
♪ So let it out and let it in ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  開始 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude, begin ♪
♪ 你在期待有人 ♪
♪ You're waiting for someone ♪
♪ 和你一起 ♪
♪ To perform with ♪
♪ 你要明白  只有靠自己 ♪
♪ And don't you know that it's just you ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  你行的 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude, you'll do ♪
♪ 未來肩負 ♪
♪ The movement you need ♪
♪ 在你身 ♪
♪ Is on your shoulder ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦  耶 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah, yeah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 別沮喪 ♪
♪ Don't make it bad ♪
♪ 唱首悲傷的歌 舒緩一下自己 ♪
♪ Take a sad song and make it better ♪
♪ 記得去理解它 ♪
♪ Remember to let her under your skin ♪
♪ 世界就能 ♪
♪ Then you'll begin ♪
♪ 開始好轉 ♪
♪ To make it better ♪
♪ 更好  更好  更好 ♪
♪ Better, better, better, better, better ♪
♪ 求求你 ♪
♪ I'm begging you ♪
♪ 哦  耶 ♪
♪ Oh! Yeah... ♪
♪ 啦啦啦  耶耶耶 ♪
♪ Nah, nah, nah-nah, nah-nah Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah... ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 裘德  裘德  哇 ♪
♪ Jude, Judy, Judy, Judy, Judy, Judy, ow, wow! ♪
♪ 啦啦啦   天啊 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah. Oh, my, my, my ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 裘德  裘德  裘德 ♪
♪ Jude, Jude, Jude, Jude, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶  啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah. Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  相信自己  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude. Yeah, you know you can make it, Jude ♪
♪ 裘德  你無法打破 ♪
♪ Jude, you're not gonna break it ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 別沮喪  裘德  啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Don't make it bad, Jude. Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 唱首悲傷的歌  舒緩一下自己 ♪
♪ Take a sad song and make it better ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  裘德  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪ ♪ Oh, Jude, Jude, hey, Jude ♪
♪ 哇 ♪
♪ Wow... ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 哦  裘德  啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Ooh, Jude ♪ - ♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 哦  耶 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  嘿 ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 現在  裘德  裘德 ♪
♪ Now, Jude, Jude, Jude, Jude, Jude ♪
♪ 啦啦啦  耶耶耶 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah. Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 哦  耶  耶 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah-nah-nah- nah-nah-nah-nah-nah-nah... ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 傷痛不再來  裘德 ♪
♪ Pain won't come back, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah. Yeah... ♪
♪ 挺過去 ♪
♪ Make it through ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德  耶耶耶 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶  耶  耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah... ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude
♪ 晚上好  女士們先生們 ♪
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude ♪
♪ 然後  啦啦啦 ♪
♪ Well, then a nah, nah-nah, nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 啦  啦  啦 ♪
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah ♪
♪ 嘿  裘德 ♪
♪ Hey, Jude. ♪
字幕由explosiveskull提供  歌詞由GoldenBeard提供
Subtitles by explosiveskull Sync by GoldenBeard